Krish NAik: Everybody, please check that I'm audible or not. I've just turned on the mic, I forgot, actually. Just check I'm audible.
Krish NAik: Okay, yeah, good morning, everyone.
Krish NAik: Alright, so I think we can start today's session. That's 9-10… So, I think this is… Put my…
Krish NAik: Okay, so today, again, I'll be sharing the link if some students might have missed it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so just wait.
Krish NAik: This is the first thing, like, if last Saturday, if you have not attended the class, even if you are interested in that project, because next week, I think I'll be releasing
Krish NAik: The final list.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, in the meantime, I think, today we'll be talking about Haystack.
Krish NAik: There is nothing to discuss. I think the things that we have there, it's syntactically, it's different. Pretty much the same stuff, so…
Krish NAik: That part. Now, the next part, I think, will be talking with respect to where is my NVIDIA registration form, just wait. NVIDIA GTC event, I think Chris shared with me yesterday.
Krish NAik: Alright, this is the other link. Everybody, please do the registration for GTC. Here, this is a post from Krish, I think. Here, you will be having the link. Please do use that link.
Krish NAik: And… do register, okay? So, first step, do the registration. If you have missed last time for our main community project, okay, and then finally coming to the GTC event.
Krish NAik: NVIDIA one. Please do the registration.
Krish NAik: What is GTC? It's the annual main NVIDIA event.
Krish NAik: A lot of cool things. I think yesterday,
Krish NAik: the, NVIDIA DJ Spark also… the price got increased when I was planning to get it.
Krish NAik: But that one.
Krish NAik: Alright, first of all, complete these two things if somebody has missed it. Okay, fill up that Google form if you're interested, because today is the last time that I am sharing. After this, I won't be sharing. Neither in the chat, so just be sure you are not sharing it in the forum also. So, very specifically, students who are attending the class for them.
Krish NAik: So MS is asking, no, I asked, what else did you ask to register? Okay, there are two things. The first is that, where is that Google form? Now, I think MS, if you have done it last time.
Krish NAik: It's great, okay? So, next week, I'll be probably releasing that team-wise, AWS, GCP, and Azure stuff. Then comes that, NVIDIA GTC event, I think for that.
Krish NAik: You'll be getting something like this, so that is the other link that I have shared.
Krish NAik: Okay, so please do the registration.
Krish NAik: In person, he got the invite. Till now, I don't think he will be going.
Krish NAik: Last year event, this year, he won't be going.
Krish NAik: Okay, so complete the registration, I think, on 16 to 19th.
Krish NAik: Not Saturday, Sunday.
Krish NAik: Once you guys have done this, can you share your LinkedIn? My LinkedIn?
Krish NAik: My English stop.
Krish NAik: Where's my, mine, mine, mine, mine, mine.
Krish NAik: But everybody, please do the registration. I think this is the link which is provided from Wikipedia. So, through that, they track how many students do register.
Krish NAik: virtually.
Krish NAik: Alright, so once… so I think, and don't pay $500, I think, for a few workshops, they might ask, not, required.
Krish NAik: Alright, then comes, I think, now, this is the tutorial. Okay, now, you guys have to do it. So, there are majorly four notebooks.
Krish NAik: there is not a single thing which is not known to you. It's only syntactically different. If something is syntactically different, it doesn't make sense to discuss the same stuff, because conceptually, you guys have already done the same thing in Langchain as well as Langraph, okay? Sorry, Langchain and Lama Index.
Krish NAik: And now the same thing with respect to Haystack. Now, Haystack…
Krish NAik: I will say the Haystack community, again, it is used, but…
Krish NAik: pretty much high-level abstract things are there. Directly to me that you will be making the import, as you guys already know the core concept, so you can see a lot of clients, they have it.
Krish NAik: It is used for building RAG, you can see, content generation, RAG AI agents, multimodal AI, conversational AI, a lot of things. So, from my side, the major focus will be towards RAG, agentic RAG, multimodal stuff, so these things I have already included in the notebook.
Krish NAik: Okay, so pretty much simple call, just be sure you are using a multi-modal whenever you are trying that out, manually.
Krish NAik: So, initially start working with the notebooks. I'm sharing the GitHub link, everybody please try to make a clue. So, you can see four notebooks are here. Okay, so the first, second, third, fourth, pretty much the things you guys have already gone through.
Krish NAik: And the content of these notebooks, like.
Krish NAik: Here I have not taken, pretty much I have kept it simple, so that you can get started, and later on you can go and explore much more.
Krish NAik: Majorly, I feel that it's good in some cases where some manual implementations are there, Haystack has provided, but again, a lot of features are there in Haystack which is not available. Through Llama Index, or by making a hybrid solution from Langchain, we might get it.
Krish NAik: So, yes, few things are there, which are not available in neither Langshan, neither in Llama, and a few things are there which is, again, not available here. You have to get it from Llama or Langshan, okay? So, please try to do the setup, I think.
Krish NAik: And this content I created around, December, okay? So I'm… yes, around December only. I've just pushed it, so… one by one, simple notebooks, I think you can do the execution. Make it DIY.
Krish NAik: Alright. Now, this is an easy thing. Now, the next thing that I'm going to give you, that is actually tough.
Krish NAik: Okay, because this, I know that you guys can explore by yourself.
Krish NAik: And just have a check. Everybody, please take a clone, do the environment setup, and at least execute the first notebook that I have shared. Let me know if there are any problems. Okay, then coming to…
Krish NAik: Little bit off.
Krish NAik: Other things… I have already shared the Haystack AI. Please share the link again, I have joined late. Why you are joining late?
Krish NAik: Alright, just wait. Okay, I've shared the link.
Krish NAik: Perfect.
Krish NAik: Now, the next one. So, let me get the link. So, this is the… Order… Thank you.
Krish NAik: Okay, multi-arm banded here.
Krish NAik: Now, this is your next week task, okay? Next week, Saturday, I will be asking you. Now, I'm sharing this link. Try to think that, the final link that I've shared in the chat, okay? Now, how this will be beneficial in my RAG system.
Krish NAik: Okay. Now, this is such an algorithm, probably if you have not worked with these type of algorithms.
Krish NAik: It's a bit different, little bit unconventional if you're not into so much research and other stuff, but try to exclude this one, which is called the multi-armed bandits, and if you're actually enforcing these things in a rag-based algorithm, okay?
Krish NAik: So, then, really, like, how it can help you.
Krish NAik: So, a simple idea, like, if you want to do an injection of reinforcement learning algorithms in the RAG-based systems, then what happens? Because there are very, very few papers on these type of things, okay?
Krish NAik: Probably, I think, in my next cohort, I'll be including these type of algorithms. These are very much from a research perspective, so know where you will be getting these type of stuff. So, pretty much manual implementations and everything that you have to do, but explore, and then let me know. Okay, so this is, like.
Krish NAik: Bringing RL into RAG. Okay, so that's the idea.
Krish NAik: Alright, so I've added it, just keep this link bookmarked.
Krish NAik: Okay, so later on, so next Saturday, just do your research, spend at least 1 hour. It's not like in 5 minutes you can understand the topic.
Krish NAik: Okay, you have to spend at least one hour to exactly understand what is going ahead, because these type of things, I don't know if somebody has previously worked on, but at least if it's new, spend one hour, and then try to think, use AI, use ChatGPT, use Cloud, use anything. But think about how this can be beneficial in any type of RAG system.
Krish NAik: Okay, my idea is that, how you guys can introduce reinforcement learning in rack-based systems.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: this is my main objective, so that's why I'm giving you just a simple problem. So there are many, many algorithms that I can say, but let's start, this is one of the easiest ones. Okay, so I feel that if you spend one hour, then simply you can get it.
Krish NAik: Holy…
Krish NAik: We use this for large-scale marketing recommendations, yes. This is really, like, much more for building scalable solutions. These things come. Normally, nobody teaches, but,
Krish NAik: If your team is actually into research and building stuff, then it's good.
Krish NAik: So, first of all, Haystack. Everybody, please do the setup. I think the setup is pretty much easy. Take a clone of this one, okay, and most of the things…
Krish NAik: If I tell you, I think you guys know about dense embeddings, you guys know about, semantic search. So here, BM25, directly, everything is through an import. Nothing is there. R-ranking, strategies.
Krish NAik: query, expansion, few things I have kept it, which is a bit unique, okay? But,
Krish NAik: the haystack part, let me just show you. They have pretty good content here also. If you go to the, blog part.
Krish NAik: Okay, you can see a lot of use cases which are available. So, according to you, you can later on test it out, but at least go through the basics, I will say. The four notebooks will give you a high-level idea with respect to the inputs.
Krish NAik: Okay, so please try to do the setup. I think, pass your OpenAI key in .env. For now, that is the bare minimum, and get started with the notebook one.
Krish NAik: Everybody.
Krish NAik: Please ping the DocShop URL. This is the blog part.
Krish NAik: Okay, and Haystack AI has some full notebooks also that you can explore.
Krish NAik: But again, you have to understand the market is highly dominated by Langchen and Llama Index. If somebody's looking an alternate way, then, like, Haystack is a very good option.
Krish NAik: Yes.
Krish NAik: This is less bloated, I can say, because I feel Langchen and Llama is highly bloated frameworks.
Krish NAik: It means that the things which are not important from my perspective, those things also come spring installed.
Krish NAik: Okay, so the library is pretty much heavy, whereas Haystack tried to keep it much more simpler, they try to stick to the things which are much more important, and a few things which are pretty much experimental, they have moved it into the experimental module separately, just like Langchen has done it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think some integrations are there, so these type of integrations also, like, Amazon Bedrock, SageMaker. Now, all third-party integrations are directly available here, and I feel that, as compared to LandChain.
Krish NAik: And, Lama Index, the documentation is better. If you are really working with this one, okay, it becomes easier. So, like, something can be a model provider, something can be a document store.
Krish NAik: So, everything, the tool integration set is really, really good. So, any people use it. Again, you can see Raga's integration, Snowflake, Ray… okay, so a lot of things. So, in production.
Krish NAik: many prefer, but again, totally up to you, because right now, I have already told you solutions where you really don't need neither language and neither Lama Index, okay? So, start with the first notebook.
Krish NAik: Pretty much… Easy to execute. Everybody?
Krish NAik: Have you cloned? Please let me know.
Krish NAik: Have we cloned?
Krish NAik: how UVSync will work, if somebody's asking UV Sync, can you see here any file?
Krish NAik: this project I created around the month of December, okay? So, there won't be any UV here. If there is no pipeproject.tuml file, here you have to do uvpipinstall requirement.txt.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: If… always look into the codebase and then take the decision. It's not like blindly start working with the UGSync.
Krish NAik: just look at, at least to work with everything, do you have the pyproject.tuml file? If it is not available, then simply, like, your normal site, uvvnv.vnv, then activate the virtual environment, and then perform an ubpy install.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: And I think, in your .env.env, yes. In your .env, you just need the OpenAI API key. The other integrations, I have kept it, but, for now, only the OpenAI API key, just pass it, and you can do rest of your work.
Krish NAik: Alright, I have kept the implementations very, very minimal, because my idea was that you guys get used to the syntax. So, spend some time. It's pretty much… you can do it by yourself. I don't think that I need to teach anything here, because syntax teaching is not my main objective, okay?
Krish NAik: If you really look into… now, these are the imports, and I think you guys are smart enough by this time to work with these type of imports. Yes or no?
Krish NAik: Tell me.
Krish NAik: When you look into a document, what is the purpose of document? It is same as in LangChain, it is same as in…
Krish NAik: Llama Index, there is no difference. Now, here, there is a pipeline concept, so through a pipeline, you can actually integrate multiple things in one shot. Now, those examples are there, as simple as that.
Krish NAik: Okay, so it's not chunks document, you have to understand, like, through to… now, the original document, you can break it at a later point, if you want. Then there are retrievers, the in-memory BM25 retrievers, so what is the purpose of this? BM25?
Krish NAik: Can I say a sparse search that happens?
Krish NAik: Yes or no?
Krish NAik: A sparse vector search.
Krish NAik: Simply, can I say that?
Krish NAik: Okay, now, the type of… I've not done any integration with any external vector databases, but you can do that. Okay? So, for now, I've just kept, majorly everything, like, in memory for now, so that you guys can quickly get started with the first notebook, and later on, you guys can play with the syntax.
Krish NAik: Okay, so just have a check, because I have checked the notebooks in the morning, so pretty much, like, I feel that most of the things are working.
Krish NAik: Because few things got,
Krish NAik: Updated, I have changed that. Only the LLM initialization part that got updated. REST, I feel, it's working fine.
Krish NAik: So… Once you have done the execution quickly, you can use the Run All button.
Krish NAik: Okay, or do shift-enter, shift, enter, shift-enter continuously, just to have a check. So, in the meantime, just look into the syntax, because it's only syntactically different. Conceptually, it's pretty much the same stuff.
Krish NAik: setting up the VNB, alright, fine, take your time, because these things, again, I am not going to say line by line, because I know it's pretty much the same stuff that you guys have already worked with.
Krish NAik: Only… syntactically, if something is different, you can easily adapt it.
Krish NAik: So spend some time, I think, with 4 notebooks, you can execute it by, today only.
Krish NAik: is… that's why. It's a simple do-it-yourself DIY task from my side. Today's session is just check, and later on, just do the analysis, because I can share that, just wait. Haystack AI GitHub, let me just open that also.
Krish NAik: Haystacked good.
Krish NAik: Hub, huh?
Krish NAik: Baystruct.
Krish NAik: There are some collab integrations, this also you can check if you feel that. You don't want to go with the basics.
Krish NAik: I think, okay, yes, there are some cookbooks.
Krish NAik: Okay, yes, so this is a haystack cookbook. I can say that, yes, these get updated with respect to time, and a lot of, I can say, cool examples are here that you can really check it out. A lot of integrations.
Krish NAik: The number of notebooks are really high, but, do have a check based on that. So, few things might be deprecated, you need to update the codebase, even their team hasn't done it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… but I have a check. I feel that a lot of things might be there which you have not, like, which you might integrate it into your own systems.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I'm sharing this haystack cookbook that you can check from here.
Krish NAik: No, no, no, not tomorrow, next week, Saturday, Saturday, Aniroth.
Krish NAik: In today's class, just go through this, and by next week, just be sure that you are…
Krish NAik: working on this one, because this prospect, at least 5 people or 10 people, if you are going through this, how it can be beneficial in rag-based systems. This part, really, I want to get your thoughts about.
Krish NAik: All right, fine. The first notebook, if it's working fine, then move to the second notebook, third notebook, fourth notebook, everybody. Okay, and don't blindly at least read the cell once, okay? Because I know the code is easy.
Krish NAik: And it's easy to understand art, okay, but at least go through. Syntactically, a little bit different, but again, the functionality is pretty much seems just like Lama.
Krish NAik: So if you… if anybody knows two frameworks, okay, the third framework is always easy to learn.
Krish NAik: What browser do you use for… This is DIA.
Krish NAik: DIA, DIA, from the browser company.
Krish NAik: Let me see… last 5 days ago, these two notebooks were there. Alright, agent-powered retrieval approach.
Krish NAik: Even I am checking, because even I have not checked, these things always. Okay, I got it, which…
Krish NAik: Okay, he's an IA.
Krish NAik: You, sir.
Krish NAik: Load dataset.
Krish NAik: Here, for everything, you have a function. That is the best thing. It means that
Krish NAik: If you know the basics, it's much easier. For example, can you see here? Fast embeds, fast document embedded.
Krish NAik: That is one of the basic things. It means that the integration of sparse embed, otherwise, separately, you have to install the package in Langchain, Llama Index, and then you have to do the… create your sparse embeddings. So, here, the direct import is there. Really good to see these things.
Krish NAik: Majorly, your implementation becomes much easier, but very high level and very, like, high abstraction, you have to understand.
Krish NAik: For beginners, that's why I don't suggest haystack. If you're comfortable with Lang Channel Llama, then only move to Hay.
Krish NAik: Because haystack is something like everything in high level, through imports.
Krish NAik: You, write lesson logic, again, directly through anything if you look into here, retriever, embedder, okay, the imports will be very, very big.
Krish NAik: Getting warning, Satish is telling, fail to hardlink files, failing back to full copy.
Krish NAik: No, no, no, see, UV link mode, Satish, I'm not using, like, UV sync or anything. Why you are getting this one?
Krish NAik: Like, I can look into that, but,
Krish NAik: Because, please use ubpip install and then hyphen r requirement.txt. Use that way.
Krish NAik: What is the advantage?
Krish NAik: You have to write always a lesser amount of code.
Krish NAik: Have you worked with PyTorch and PyTorch Lightning? Anybody?
Krish NAik: Like, it's simply… for example, see, if you have… let's forget, like, PyTorch, if you have worked with, okay?
Krish NAik: Now, in PyTorch, if you're doing some stuff, okay, now, the next thing just think about if you are working with Kira.
Krish NAik: Can I say that Keros is very high level?
Krish NAik: Both the frameworks. It just framework is different. Like, Keras is always easy, so simply haystack. Everything is function. You cannot really understand what is going behind the scenes. But with respect to PyTorch, you can really understand. Then, same thing here. Here, everything is through an import.
Krish NAik: Pretty much functional-based approach, I can say. For everything, you have class and functions.
Krish NAik: Rather than doing a scratch implementation. I hope you get that. So, Haystack is preferred by a lot of… you know that when it becomes much more functional, like TensorQu, if I say, okay, TensorQu and Keras.
Krish NAik: It is used for production.
Krish NAik: Lesser changes as compared to Llama and Langchain community always get very, very quick updates.
Krish NAik: But here, yes, it takes time. It's not like that at every hour, at every point. Yes, they do updates, but the stability, they focus much more on stability.
Krish NAik: So, in production, they prefer it. And less bloating is there. I hope everybody understands, like, bloated frameworks.
Krish NAik: In production, you don't need every feature, rather than focusing on the main features which are actually needed, so keeping things much lesser bloated.
Krish NAik: So that's why they prefer. And they have, really, a lot of plans. Making things something lightweight, so that's why the preference always comes.
Krish NAik: And they do have the dedicated enterprise one, so you can check out their trial also. But, there are few organizations, and mainly European con… in European, I have seen countries, they are using it.
Krish NAik: European and U.S. In India, less I can say.
Krish NAik: Others can provide me a confirmation for everybody, the first notebook, second notebook, like, if you guys are testing it out, it's working fine or not.
Krish NAik: Just remember, Lama Index is more powerful, if we tell now, any framework that I've discussed, my personal choice is Lama.
Krish NAik: Yes, Haystack, every framework has an agentic workflow.
Krish NAik: everything, AWS, GCP, like, there are more than, like, 200 major frameworks providers for building agents now, in the market. Everybody's building their own.
Krish NAik: No, no, no, open claw is different. Open claw…
Krish NAik: It's totally different. Anybody has done the setup for OpenClaw?
Krish NAik: Yes, and done any type of coding stuff, like code generation or anything?
Krish NAik: OpenClaw, how many of you have done it?
Krish NAik: No, just hard, could you please ping the link of the integration page?
Krish NAik: integration page. Just open the main Haystack website.
Krish NAik: This is so good.
Krish NAik: Yes, open claw… because I'm… for OpenClaw, right now, I can say that the setup is much easier.
Krish NAik: I've done it, I will say it's good, but the response time is… somehow, I feel it's towards the higher side. If you want one-liner setup, you can do it in your own system, and you can try it out.
Krish NAik: But only for personal things, never use it in enterprise.
Krish NAik: That's… that's tough.
Krish NAik: Pfft.
Krish NAik: I've tested it out, and I think, there is one integration, like, I've used it in Hostinger, I took in BPS, and in that BPS, I did the setup.
Krish NAik: Just set up.
Krish NAik: it's much easier in a BPS-based system, so I have done it there.
Krish NAik: And, I think that was the requirement, because there is a campaign which is being launched by the Hostinger team, so they asked,
Krish NAik: Like, to create the video for that, like, one click annotated deployment, then one click open for deployment for those things.
Krish NAik: Is OpenCloud based on context engineering?
Krish NAik: Context engineering is different.
Krish NAik: I prefer, like, always focusing on the core functionality. I don't prefer always working with Langchen, neither Llama Index.
Krish NAik: It means that if I don't have anything, if I feel that my custom implementation will take a lot of time.
Krish NAik: then only I can go ahead. Otherwise, like, Langchain and Llama, these things are very much looted.
Krish NAik: The level of glutenals of heat stack is lesser as compared to others.
Krish NAik: I feel that if you want to work with a VectorDB, use a VectorDB official package.
Krish NAik: It's, like, it's better, you will get better speeds.
Krish NAik: Okay, the integration is much better, like, for everything. By GLAT requirement, try to use that exact package.
Krish NAik: Don't take an integrated package, like Langchen provides, for LangChain OpenAI, LangChain Anthropic, Langgen, for everything, it doesn't make sense. It means that they are creating a library, then another, on top of that, another wrapper, so wrapper, wrapper, wrapper, so many levels of wrappers are not required. Keep things lightweight.
Krish NAik: And really, like, I feel that the amount of cookbooks which are provided by Haystack are really good. So, you can pick a few of the things which might be relevant in your case, and you can do an integration.
Krish NAik: Okay, like, information extraction through Raven. I really, like.
Krish NAik: In 2026, nobody will be using Raven. How many of you know about Raven?
Krish NAik: Anybody knows about Raven?
Krish NAik: Yes.
Krish NAik: Not okay. Revan is actually a model, per se.
Krish NAik: Which is used.
Krish NAik: In the field of information retrieval.
Krish NAik: A lot of things are there which are old, but you can look into the last 3 to 4 months of implementation.
Krish NAik: Like, memo is there all right. Metadata enrichment, okay, now this is something, like, you can look into. Probably in the next class, I can, little bit talk about that.
Krish NAik: Now, this is using LLM. These guys will be using an LLM to do this, okay? Trafalutra, okay, another few things, but this is purely based on LLM-based approach, yes. OpenAI key.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Fine. I'll be showing you an approach without an… rather than focusing much more on entity-based approach.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I'll be taking one class for metadata enrichment, but my way is a little bit different. Always not focusing on LLM. Focusing on LLM is much easier, you know that. But I feel that it's a costlier task, rather than using something like lank extract.
Krish NAik: How many of you know about Lang Extract?
Krish NAik: I have told so many times in this pro that anybody have extract?
Krish NAik: This is from Google. This is nothing related to LanChain ecosystem. Totally different.
Krish NAik: Yeah, I'm really good, I can say.
Krish NAik: Okay, converting your unstructured data into structured text, this is widely used. You can look into the number of stars, and highly, good project, I can say. So, I'll be showing you, like, using lang extract, how you can do that.
Krish NAik: Generally, on top of your chunk, you have to apply, and very similarly, you have to pick up some rules.
Krish NAik: One is Lang Extract, and the other one, I do have two implementations, I'll be sharing both of them.
Krish NAik: A land transfer is much more recent, so I prefer this. I do have another version also.
Krish NAik: In memory, document store makes vector DB redundant and correct.
Krish NAik: It's only for local, no, but that is not persistent, Jagaphat. We need persistent, storage, so for that, we need dedicated vector DBs.
Krish NAik: Dinesh is asking, no, no, no, Raven is a very separate model which make, tool calling, features. Through that, you extract data.
Krish NAik: It is used majorly for, the purpose of, retrieval only.
Krish NAik: IR. In the field of IR, it is widely used information retributed.
Krish NAik: But it's pretty much old. Now, in 2026, nobody will be touching that.
Krish NAik: Yes. Dinesh, if you want to look into this one, I'm sharing the link.
Krish NAik: But some old stuff, that's been…
Krish NAik: I think, the first notebook is pretty much self-explanatory. There is nothing new
Krish NAik: is something like, which you might have felt that I have never done it in this particular cohort till now. Yes, anybody is feeling like that in the notebook one? Because I feel that it is damn straightforward. There is nothing to teach it.
Krish NAik: Only syntactically, the imports are different, and you were just using the imports. Please provide me the confirmation in the chat.
Krish NAik: Yes?
Krish NAik: Yes, guys, please let me know. It's pretty much self-explanatory stuff, the first notebook.
Krish NAik: How many of you have executed the first notebook? Please provide me with an ESO.
Krish NAik: Yes, all good stuff, pretty much.
Krish NAik: I always check out the, like, what are the new cookbooks that gets added?
Krish NAik: Even for Transformers, I do check out the cookbooks. Cookbooks give you a new, pressure way of, doing stuff.
Krish NAik: Proper, probably newer implementations.
Krish NAik: This is around 11th month ago. A lot of things will be deprecated, but we can actually work on that.
Krish NAik: Now, one thing, like, I'm directly showing you the notebooks, but they have a dedicated webpage. For example, if you want to check the full article here, okay?
Krish NAik: And now, let me just show you. Once I open the article, Where is the…
Krish NAik: Where is the article? For everything, they have a dedicated article.
Krish NAik: They have removed it, it looks like.
Krish NAik: Yeah, really, it was good, the cookbook and the full… article, nobody has, nothing is found, alright.
Krish NAik: They have removed those links, I feel.
Krish NAik: Previously, it was there, and I feel that it was good.
Krish NAik: Yes, that is collab notebook, did you keep in GitHub? I didn't kept it in GitHub. I can add that.
Krish NAik: Just wait, I will add that. If you feel that, because the link is there in Notion, so I didn't add it. If you want, I can do it.
Krish NAik: because that notebook, you cannot execute it outside an collab environment, then you have to do those secret changes. Okay, just wait, then I will push that.
Krish NAik: Are you working on a Haystack AI tutorial?
Krish NAik: No, no, no, like, Haystack AI?
Krish NAik: later on, like, I'm working on an Udemy course. There, right now, my main focus is Llama. Okay, and later on, I will be taking… adding a few things with respect to Hashtag. The same thing, the same notebook. The things that I've taught in class, the same things I'll be recording. There won't be much difference. Only the versions and other things, probably, like, after 2 months.
Krish NAik: Only the versional changes will be there, pretty much the same boiler data I'll be using there also.
Krish NAik: Okay, just wait, let me then open… Colorado.
Krish NAik: And, last class, how many of you have executed this particular notebook?
Krish NAik: Last class. Building the knowledge graph.
Krish NAik: Yes, how many of you have executed it, and you really understood that making dynamical changes in your graph
Krish NAik: By using Gravity. This is really a good one, I will say, that
Krish NAik: you can spend more time on this, because Falker is also, like, one…
Krish NAik: I think one product which highly promotes building graphite.
Krish NAik: Okay, and
Krish NAik: like, I can say in 2024, building a graph rack was much more costlier operation. As compared to 2026, it has become much cheaper, I can say.
Krish NAik: So, yes, everybody is attaching, like, the third leg. The first is that sparse, dense, and the third leg is this one. Okay, so I have seen, majorly, like, everybody is taking that particular implementation.
Krish NAik: Like, I can say the integrations… now the same integration of graphite can be done using Neo4j also.
Krish NAik: Okay, the same integration, there is no different.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I'm just telling you, this is the actual…
Krish NAik: Why this page is not opening.
Krish NAik: Zep.dev, have they changed the domains?
Krish NAik: Not right now, the… okay, now from here, as you can see, okay, so majorly, like, new 4J, AWS, Neptune, can you see these are the majorly used graph databases? Okay, so GraphIT can sit on top of anyone.
Krish NAik: So I cannot see a lot, like ArangoDB and others, which are not included here, but I feel that, yes.
Krish NAik: At least you can do your main testing. If you don't want to go with Falker, it's fine. At least do the testing with Neo4J.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Rahul is asking, can you, explain, alright, yes?
Krish NAik: what to explain here? They have a simple, I can see, haystack, certain components that they have defined it.
Krish NAik: Like, I can take a clone of this one if you want this, because there are so many packages here I can see.
Krish NAik: This is the package. You have to install the package in your system, and then you have to start working on that route.
Krish NAik: the number of packages are quite high. You have to perform, like, pip install, and then, like, haystack core integrations, and through that.
Krish NAik: This is a complete module that they have built.
Krish NAik: And this is the actual one, through integrations, I can see they are going inside that particular Bedrock page, and here, another integration, few PyDocs. And right now, if I look into the examples, re-ranker.
Krish NAik: But again, like, see, if you want to use haystack in AWS and fraud.md, it means that where you will be executing that haystack, that you have to take.
Krish NAik: Like, through Lambda, you want to invoke something, or you need a dedicated EC2 instance to do that.
Krish NAik: Like, what will be the major thing? Because I don't feel that you need haystack.
Krish NAik: I guess.
Krish NAik: Because directly, I can work with Boto packages there. I hope you get it, Raul. Because if I want to use better rack, I know my direct package is Bhuto. Why not work directly with Bhuto, rather than going around with a third wheel? I hope you get my point.
Krish NAik: For text-to-SQL, text-to-SQL, if you want to do any implementation, then I will use much better Icon7 as compared to Haystack. Haystack is not highly used for only text-to-SQL.
Krish NAik: Pick up those components which are only good at that thing, rather than picking up a generic thing which does everything.
Krish NAik: Mmm… Hey, Stack, you are asking text to NoSQL.
Krish NAik: Alright, text to NoSQL… Even I'm not sure about that.
Krish NAik: text to NoSQL, I don't think NoSQL direct.
Krish NAik: Now, this is a MongoDB integration, now this is different, but you can see here, there is an example, but again, this is with respect to SQL databases.
Krish NAik: I don't think our direct integration is there with respect to
Krish NAik: The new hashtag, this is a different integration. Through hashtag, if you want to read some data in your Mongo, that is that integration that they are talking about.
Krish NAik: But, this is not, the one that you are talking, text to NoSQL.
Krish NAik: No, this is different. Like, through a stack, if you want to call your MongoDB install, now that is the purpose. I don't think it is available.
Krish NAik: Yes, whoever is asking about that. Directly, it's not there.
Krish NAik: Why now you embed in ECS container and invoke the desired AWS? So, why now you embed it in a ECS container? Yes, possible, and invoke the desired AWS bedrock.
Krish NAik: And invoke. Generally, like, invoking any bedrock models, whether re-ranking models, embedding models, or anything, my main choice will be through an AWS Lambda wrapper.
Krish NAik: ECSY. ECS, I feel that ECS will be much costlier.
Krish NAik: If you ask me.
Krish NAik: continuously do you need those services? That is the first thing around. I hope you get my point. You only need to invoke them just for one query, and then you really don't need the service.
Krish NAik: If you need that continuous service, then only I will go ahead with ECS contain. I hope I made my point.
Krish NAik: Hmm…
Krish NAik: And, please spend some time even in the documentation. The documentation is not, really, like, a big one. Okay, so here, everything comes under a pipeline, okay, like, creating pipelines.
Krish NAik: through a pipeline, you can add everything. Can you see? Like, 3 separate things are there, and later on, you can just create a pipeline, and inside the pipeline, one by one, you can add each component.
Krish NAik: So, that is, the benefit. It means that your text embedded, whatever you can initialize, one by one.
Krish NAik: So this is a very, very easy approach. Very high-level approach, I can say. Developer-friendly approach.
Krish NAik: Let us… Like, Langchen is less developer-friendly.
Krish NAik: Llama is at least developer-friendly, I can say.
Krish NAik: And he said, highly…
Krish NAik: So it becomes easier for any new developer to get adopted to these things. Here's SQL and Pipeline, pretty much. Even Transformers Pipeline, if you have worked with Transformers Pipeline, very similar thing.
Krish NAik: This is direct LLM-based implementation.
Krish NAik: So, implementation might be helpful to you, but really, I can say that
Krish NAik: probably 5% or 10% that you might feel which is required in your case. Otherwise, I'm also not really a fan of haystack, but again, an optional one. If you're comfortable with language and Llama Index, I feel that any other framework, you can very easily adopt it.
Krish NAik: So… And how many have executed the second notebook? Please let me know, the second notebook.
Krish NAik: Working?
Krish NAik: Yes?
Krish NAik: Second notebook.
Krish NAik: Second notebook, anything new in second notebook that you've read? Because the concepts are exactly the same.
Krish NAik: Because I think few advancing that I've kept it in the third notebook, and probably, I think, few things in the fourth notebook. Those things can be a little bit interesting. But first notebook, nothing to discuss.
Krish NAik: And second notebook, also nothing to discuss so much. So, please complete the execution of these two notebooks.
Krish NAik: Need to understand and run, so taking a little bit, yes, read the code, don't blindly do Shift-Enter, Shift-Enter, at least read the code, because syntactically it's different, but you have to make sense that how this is a similar approach that you can create it there in Langchen or in LAMA. Try to make that. No, no, Anthropic API is not required, only one API is required, which is your, OpenAI.
Krish NAik: I've given multiple options there, but my main integration here, if I show you where is tutorial is. So here, in the .env example, you don't need to add, only one thing just added here.
Krish NAik: Later on, even for Coher, I was planning, later on, I have switched it to sentence transformers.
Krish NAik: Okay, so from Sentence Transformers, you guys know that what is the alternate? Open source?
Krish NAik: Model name, quickly tell me.
Krish NAik: For your re-ranking.
Krish NAik: For your real anchor, what is that free model that I have taught you in class?
Krish NAik: It should be directly, like, I… not Mar… okay, Marco, okay, yes, the Marco model, MS Marco, yes.
Krish NAik: Always remember that.
Krish NAik: for everyone, at least. If you have worked, then even in interviews that blindly, like, quickly you can say that.
Krish NAik: And I think, for one of the cases here, server API is required, guys. I think in the third notebook, probably, there, because CRAG and those things I've already taught you, a very similar implementation of CRAG is there.
Krish NAik: Okay, so current… the case of corrective rack, where you don't get responses from your vector DB, so the fallback is
Krish NAik: For a Google search. So, for that, you need to create your own server API. And I think for everybody, they can create their Serpa API. The link is already given here.
Krish NAik: sarpat.dev slash API key.
Krish NAik: So, Jagaphat is asking, rag underscore pipeline, connect retriever prompt builder. Isn't it supposed to be connect the retriever and the prompt? Why documents within the…
Krish NAik: Retriever and Prompt.
Krish NAik: Like, white documents within the retriever and the prompt?
Krish NAik: Within the retriever, I could not get that part.
Krish NAik: Because in a pipeline you attach, what are the things that has been defined? Like, the retriever definition that has been defined, and the prompt builder.
Krish NAik: Anything that comes under a pipeline, the initialization. Now, that is the same thing that I was showing you in the documentation also, I think.
Krish NAik: Okay, anything that you do define, whether… whatever the things, like here, document store, text embedder, retriever, these are the component initialization, and later on, you can add it through add component.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: And how to connect all those components, so this one, if you want to do.
Krish NAik: So, pipeline.connectjo. Okay, so first of all, just be sure you are adding the components on later on. If you don't want to do it directly, just, now, what helps you? Like, if you want to connect the output of one to another one, in those cases, it gives you a better visualization idea.
Krish NAik: So at least look into the talks.
Krish NAik: Now, visualization is not really required, I feel, for most of you, so in this case.
Krish NAik: But, it gives you that entire pipeline diagram through that you can actually pass it.
Krish NAik: Certain features, like, device management, if you want to do it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, like, the Hugging Face Local Generator, Azure OpenAI Generator.
Krish NAik: like, if you are really working with GPUs in those cases, few things might be beneficial for you. I think these functionalities are not available in Lansion or in Lama. Device management.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, just think that there's a certain, I can say.
Krish NAik: I can say operations. So for now, in this one, can you see, this is a local model, Hugging Face Local Generator. And here, probably, you need access to GPUs.
Krish NAik: So, in that case, his stack has that particular support.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, manually in LandChain or in Llama, you have to create a PyTorch function. Through that PyTorch, you need to get the device, and you need to attach it.
Krish NAik: You know, that's why, like, few things are there, which are then again, like, attaching Jinja templates with your agents.
Krish NAik: Now, this is very specific to agents that they have attached it. Now, Jinja templates, how many of you worked with these type of Python F strings? Anybody?
Krish NAik: Jinja Wedge templating feature is available in Flask. If anybody has learned Flask, they're also.
Krish NAik: In Flask, you do this particular operation.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Okay, like Langshan Experimental, there is a, Haystack Experimental also, and a few features.
Krish NAik: So, additional cookbooks, you can see, like, a conversational rag, okay, newsletter sending agent, but, we will be working with memo. Okay, memo and, let's see, with respect to the memory implementation, okay, because in future classes, I think next week, I'll be talking about…
Krish NAik: One is, hmm… Gibson.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Just wait, I think, like, we just opened Google, and then…
Krish NAik: Okay, now, from memory labs, Kepsonia, yeah.
Krish NAik: Memory implementation that, they have done it through,
Krish NAik: Okay, hold it. This is a good one, memory.
Krish NAik: And, like, really, like, let me switch to the Python one.
Krish NAik: the support is there. Otherwise, there is one paper. Anybody has it? Paper.
Krish NAik: And that is.
Krish NAik: Yes, this is the other product which got famous a lot in the past 6 months.
Krish NAik: Okay, so paper combines vector embeddings, knowledge graphs, and one simple AP and MCP, or predictive memory.
Krish NAik: This is also getting used, I can say. But, in free, basic operations only, I can show you.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this product also got, funding, and then finally comes our memo.
Krish NAik: Okay, so…
Krish NAik: This is the mem0, or MEMO, this. So, two things that we'll be talking about, any integration that we can do.
Krish NAik: what is the advantage? It's a framework thing, there is no advantage of… through Jinja templating, like, you can, like, create your main templates, like in, HTML templates, it can be… it can be Python-based template, any type of templating feature if you need, so Jinja actually helps you.
Krish NAik: Even in fast API Jinja templates can be integrated, the niche.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think next week we'll be talking about this, and then… because for,
Krish NAik: Now the question comes for multimodal rack-based systems, exactly. Like, what are the things that… because I am planning to go ahead with Docklink. Okay, Docklink runite. They have a good support.
Krish NAik: If I go ahead with minor U, minor U, you need more VRAM.
Krish NAik: Okay, so probably I need to switch to… if you have, just wait.
Krish NAik: Like, minor view. Minoru is good, I can say. This is from the Open Data Lab. So, Open Data Lab…
Krish NAik: provide very, I can say good one, you can say GitHub trending number one. But you need very high RAM. You cannot perform these things simply.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: And, demo in Hugging Face is there, I think, that you can check it out. So, majorly in the multimodal part, I'll be working with different type of OCRs.
Krish NAik: It can be, like, DeepSeq OCR, even the DeepSeek OCR V2 version. Anybody have tested these? Because I need to show you OCRs much more, at least 3 to 4 different types of OCRs for your multimodal parsing.
Krish NAik: Granite is good, it's easy, but at least you need VRAM. Without a VRAM, you cannot do these things.
Krish NAik: Yeah, so any type of, like, PDF extraction demo, so there are certain, spaces which are created. Now.
Krish NAik: to do this thing, we need good amount of VR. Can you see here? It's running on L40S. I hope you get it, just to show the demo. You need a continuous GPU which is running. Without a GPU, it is not possible.
Krish NAik: Hmm…
Krish NAik: Yes, I can see, because once you start exploring things much more, okay, I can see. And here, the output is, like, you will be passing the PDF, and all those tables and everything that you have, the final output you'll be getting in markdown entering. So, a really good one.
Krish NAik: But again, Chinese, tough. If you don't want Chinese, you can work with IBM. Okay, so IBM, as you can see.
Krish NAik: So, there are multiple granite models, so this one I'll be discussing.
Krish NAik: And the other implementation, just return.
Krish NAik: I think I have done that.
Krish NAik: Because the list of OCRs are really long.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think Nimote wrong.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is the other one from NVIDIA.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: So… Like, this one, also, I'm planning.
Krish NAik: Okay, to discuss.
Krish NAik: The Chinese stuff, though it's good, but in production, you know, very less…
Krish NAik: People stay away from Chinese stuff, okay? Though they might perform very good.
Krish NAik: But, I know that IBM and NVIDIA, these two will be the standards that we can follow, yes? Then I will go ahead with these two things.
Krish NAik: The list for OCS is really long, so if I show you this one, this paper came around, like, 25th November, and here are a hell lot of OCS that they have listed.
Krish NAik: I think, multilingual synthetic, okay, a few modality structures.
Krish NAik: Cosmos… okay, yes, now this is the list of OCRs that you can see.
Krish NAik: Majorly. Like, they have done the testing, so I feel that, first of all, simple ones, marker, if you… can you see here, minus 2.1, Monkey OCR,
Krish NAik: These guys have already done it. Now.
Krish NAik: DeepSeek OCR version 2 came later on, so they have included the version 1. So I feel that these are end-to-end models through which you can do, like, small dock link. Can you see here?
Krish NAik: I will be picking up small docklink worm. But the list of OCRs are really long, because next week, I'll be starting with the multimodal stuff, so at least a high-level idea.
Krish NAik: So this paper, I feel, if you have time, you can go ahead, and can you see, like, these are cloud-based services.
Krish NAik: How many of you can understand when you look into these things quickly? Like, text track.
Krish NAik: GPT 4.0, because GPT 4.0 also has a multimodal support.
Krish NAik: The same thing, like, through Azure also, you can access it, Llama Pars, gcloud, unstructured.
Krish NAik: Now, this is a task based on table similarity. So, I need a paper who has done the benchmarking, so I'll be picking up NVIDIA. I feel that NVIDIA… well, there are a lot of Chinese papers who have done it, but let's go with the standard one.
Krish NAik: Honigo, the Abbey OCR, abby, OCR, like, it's… I've not used Abbey OCR.
Krish NAik: But, I have to check on that one.
Krish NAik: The link of this paper, alright.
Krish NAik: Because even I was thinking about what to include in your multimodal parsing.
Krish NAik: Because I need to keep things a little bit lightweight, so that everybody can execute.
Krish NAik: There is the lightest and the best OCR model if I have worked with. The lightest one is from NanoNets.
Krish NAik: Anybody knows about nanoNets?
Krish NAik: They have the lightest one.
Krish NAik: This is, very, very light, and I really prefer… you can see downloads last month. It got, like, very, very famous when things comes around.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is very, very lightweight, and the output quality is really good.
Krish NAik: I'll be talking about a lot of OCRs, then another one from Tencent, that, Munan OCR.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that is also good to partake in the setup.
Krish NAik: OCR, Palestinian.
Krish NAik: How many of you know about Tencent, this one? Anybody has heard about Tencent?
Krish NAik: Anybody play the games?
Krish NAik: In your, mobile, or… Tencent, very… they have a good, research division. PUBG owner, yeah.
Krish NAik: Okay, so for image processing, video processing.
Krish NAik: Things are different, a little bit.
Krish NAik: So, that's why now, from here only, that, Huna knows here, this one. Very less people have tested it, but, the overall benchmarks, I feel that it's really good as compared to others. But again, Chinese stuff, so people stay away.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: In OCRs, really, the market is, like, a lot of things are there. Which one to pick up, even sometimes…
Krish NAik: I get confused. Majorly, I say that, go ahead with the cloud providers. And majorly, most organizations does that. They're simply, whatever is their own cloud provider, they stick to that. It doesn't matter whether it's good or bad.
Krish NAik: But they will stick.
Krish NAik: Because my favorite service is Azure Doc Intelligence.
Krish NAik: If I want to perform any type of search task, and if I want to stick to cloud. AWS is also good, but in some cases, I feel that somehow it has performed better. So, little bit aligned towards that.
Krish NAik: Alright, 57 responses I have received.
Krish NAik: Mmm… alright, great. About 5 to 10 hours.
Krish NAik: 20% account.
Krish NAik: Amar is asking… If you are late, I've given you that, GitHub, and from there you can start. I am not doing any execution today, because I feel
Krish NAik: That you guys can do the execution.
Krish NAik: Mmm, so I think, have I downloaded it? Yes.
Krish NAik: Just wait, I will update, this one in yesterday's… Took us solely.
Krish NAik: I think this is your graph, right?
Krish NAik: So whoever is requested, I am just pushing that particular change.
Krish NAik: Okay, so…
Krish NAik: yesterday's report, I have updated it.
Krish NAik: Just be sure you are updating the…
Krish NAik: Secrets part, because here the secret is…
Krish NAik: picking up from collab environment, you have to make changes in the code so that it picks up from your .env.
Krish NAik: This is yesterday's report that I have updated now.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, let me know how many of you have executed the other notebooks?
Krish NAik: The third notebook, how many of you have executed?
Krish NAik: Because I feel the third notebook, let me just open, anti-gravity. Yes?
Krish NAik: Third notebook is having… Which one? Okay, RAG, RAG.
Krish NAik: Conditional routing is there, I think probably then CRAG will come into the picture.
Krish NAik: I'm getting error in the second notebook, all right, in the second notebook, and where you are getting the error, you can let me know. People who are getting the error, please let me know, because I think that it should work in your system.
Krish NAik: I'm getting the error in the second notebook, re-ranking. R-ranking, alright. In re-ranking, what is the error? Can you please let me know?
Krish NAik: Because,
Krish NAik: In the second notebook, like, in which section? 3.3, tell me that.
Krish NAik: Yes, I know that accelerate module needs to be added to fix the rearranging. If you do the installation of, I think, transformers, with the transformers, it comes pre-installed.
Krish NAik: Yeah, so, alright.
Krish NAik: Today I have opened the chat, so anybody can type in the chat, don't, just paste it to me, host and panelists. Today's chat is pretty much open at this, simple general discussion.
Krish NAik: And biology shared like Transformers Torch.
Krish NAik: because in my, requirement.txt, I have already kept that inside this, these two are commented versions, okay? Actually, like, when you do the installation of these two.
Krish NAik: Okay, automatically it will be handled.
Krish NAik: Hmm…
Krish NAik: Yeah, so I've kept it as a uncommented version, but you can use that.
Krish NAik: Because other than that, in the second notebook, also… not…
Krish NAik: Anything, where? Any others, please let me know in the second notebook. Anybody else getting any errors?
Krish NAik: Other than re-ranking, the re-ranking solution already told in the chat, please do the installation of the package, it will be resolved.
Krish NAik: Yes, we have to write. Now, actually, like, if you're into things now, because for the next cohort, actually, for rank.2, a lot of things that I will remove, and then I'm thinking about, like, picking up, and bringing few things. Probably, I will remove the haystack module.
Krish NAik: A few other things I will remove from, I will only teach, I will remove unstructured also. I will only stick to Dockling and Llama Parse.
Krish NAik: a lot of things that I'll be making it much more compact, and probably within, I can say.
Krish NAik: 4 months that we can actually wrap up this.
Krish NAik: Because the research papers are really, like… and, I'm planning… yesterday, like, somebody suggested to create a dashboard for all the RAG and everything. That part I am planning, actually, because, once I have done, then probably I will create a dedicated website and I will host it.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, anything with respect to rack papers and others?
Krish NAik: And paper-based implementations, let's take step by step. I need to, like, make a few agents and make them work one by one.
Krish NAik: So that they can keep on publishing it in GitHub. So that part, I will figure it out, and then I will do. Next week, Teams. Next Saturday, I'll be talking about the Teams, okay? Don't worry.
Krish NAik: And you'll be getting a mail from my side. That,
Krish NAik: These two are the team leads, and these are the team members. Okay, so…
Krish NAik: plan, and plan your main project kickoff meeting, decide the architecture, those things, and create your own, communication channel. It can be Slack, it can be Discord, anything.
Krish NAik: I prefer much more Discord, because in the free version of Slack, everything after 2 weeks gets deleted, any talk. So, like, create your own groups, like WhatsApp, whichever is fine according to your own groups and the other members, how they are comfortable, take that decision, and try to do the incorporation according to that.
Krish NAik: You bet.
Krish NAik: In the Google form, I have mystically written, I am learning AIML since 2001, and…
Krish NAik: Okay, mail is not required, but fine.
Krish NAik: Okay, and I really, like, for RAG-based, GDs, like, another JD came to me.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… yesterday I showed you the JD also. How many of you remember the JD yesterday I showed you? The job description?
Krish NAik: Where is that job description? Job description, and yes?
Krish NAik: Yeah, so, like, this was from Nagaro.
Krish NAik: Mmm…
Krish NAik: Where is that Microsoft? Okay, yes, here, software engineer, backend. Now, really, when I looked into it, I didn't feel any… a lot of other things. If somebody has worked with machine learning-based systems.
Krish NAik: Rest of the things, now you can see latency, performance, and infra cost. This rule is someone, like, more than 4 years of experience, okay? Not for freshers completely. So, you can see experience, like, 4, I know, they can take 4 also, if somebody is very good, okay?
Krish NAik: So, like, if you want
Krish NAik: you can drop me a mail. Okay, if somebody wants to apply, if you are ready, and if you feel that I'm applying, rough estimated, you can ask
Krish NAik: 30-40. Okay. So if you want, you can drop me a mail, I can share you the link.
Krish NAik: Right now, the market is really hot in Bangalore. People are paying, like, too much.
Krish NAik: too much. I don't know, because of that, adoption in AI previously, people have might not done it, but, really, they are taking that, for now.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: No, no, not for 15 years, this is for, January, 5.527.
Krish NAik: drop me a mail, Viraj. People who want to do that, please drop me a mail at app at the registration, because if I paste it, I don't know if somebody put something, then again, the HR and other things, okay, that's why. Just keep it, tight.
Krish NAik: Is the market, anything trending go in terms of rules? Right now, I can say that,
Krish NAik: The other student from the other batch into the bag, he got
Krish NAik: Like, I can see the change with respect to the package, like, people are really… from 20 lakhs, most of the students, like, 40, 45, they have targeted very high. In the last 45 days, there are many students who has done it. So I feel that the Bangalore market, at least, is good.
Krish NAik: In Bangalore, companies are hiring, I can say.
Krish NAik: How many of you know about… there's a healthcare organization called as Optum? Optum. Anybody knows about… in Bangalore, it's a… it's paying really good now. People have done… I know, like, 4 people got there. Everybody, from 16 directly 45.
Krish NAik: Okay, and majorly, like, the RAG and LLM guys were there. So, people making high switches, you know. And those are all, like, 5-year guys, so I feel that, yes, the market is paying really good. Other organizations in Bangalore, in that, Belandur area.
Krish NAik: Many are there.
Krish NAik: Hmm, correct.
Krish NAik: For 5 years, 5 years can easily ask 30, 14 easily for me.
Krish NAik: Now, market paying you a lot, all you need. So I, like, I'm telling you, if you're looking for a switch, this is a very, very good time.
Krish NAik: Because every company, when, like, in the starting of the year, they will get a budget.
Krish NAik: Okay? And that budget is allocated to the HR to hire. So they spend, really, from the starting of February to March.
Krish NAik: Then again, like, it's down. So, this 2 months, for… I generally suggest you can go ahead. This is really a good time. New year, new budget, and right now, AI is also playing a crucial role, so they are actually paying really good.
Krish NAik: The war doesn't. That war is quite much an artificial one, so Rajput, it's not like that.
Krish NAik: Yesterday, the prices of hardware will be much higher, I can say, because NVIDIA, yesterday, they have increased that DGX price by $700.
Krish NAik: Okay, so everyone is increasing their hardware prices. Even Apple, they launched their, new M5 series, the Pro version and the Max version, even they have increased their prices as compared to previous one. Probably, I feel that $200 to $300 are increased much more.
Krish NAik: It's good, actually. Very happy, happy, I can say. Optum MS.
Krish NAik: A few, like, that is very specific to healthcare, a few financial organizations are also there, who are great. But if somebody's looking for a switch, this is really a good time.
Krish NAik: And at least the things that we have discussed for anyone, like, 1 year or 2 year of experience, easily they can get it.
Krish NAik: Okay, my email ID, APP at the red krishnak, Sam, it's pretty much the same.
Krish NAik: APPapp at the rate questionnaire.in, just drop me. If you want, I can share the link.
Krish NAik: And the market is not asking questions about LLMs, that is the other thing. Not really into the…
Krish NAik: Fine-tuning stuff… okay, really, they are not asking questions into that section a lot. Majorly, the questions are around the rack.
Krish NAik: I can say lesser towards LLM-focused. It's much more about consumption of the LLMs, rather than building SLMs or anything like that, so I will say it's good.
Krish NAik: No, package definition is different, like, 14 years, really, like, I know, like, having 10 years, they are getting good ones, like, 1.2, 1.5, so 14 years…
Krish NAik: There is no such thing. Now it's whether you are in that product-based or based on the organization, I can see.
Krish NAik: But it's a good time, like, anyone in between. There are a few others also, so drop me a mail if you're interested, I can share that, so that you can apply.
Krish NAik: So, really good time. Before March 31st, try to apply, I will say we'll get more calls than others.
Krish NAik: We did this one, I think.
Krish NAik: Okay, so MEM0, 0 and Paper, these two things that I'll be discussing in the next one, and metadata enrichment, that part I will know. Where to apply, Satish?
Krish NAik: Majority, like, knocker is good. Now, I think all the students, they are using Nocree only.
Krish NAik: Don't use LinkedIn. In LinkedIn, nobody responds, it takes a lot of time to find. I prefer much more having that direct connect. Referrals are much better.
Krish NAik: Use the referrals.
Krish NAik: Because if somebody is having any opening in their organization, post it in your group, okay? And then… referrals are the best way.
Krish NAik: And, again, I am telling you, please spend some time on this one.
Krish NAik: This is, like, it's boring stuff, but…
Krish NAik: It is interesting. If somebody is actually into research for them, it will be interesting. So, at least next class, I want to do the discussion, like, how you can inject these type of things into a rag-based system.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is simply reinforcement learning.
Krish NAik: It means that everywhere you… where you take an agent, agent, agent, but how you can build a reward-based system.
Krish NAik: In a rag.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why I've, added this one. Please try to do this.
Krish NAik: We'll implement Thomson sampling, we can do that.
Krish NAik: some sampling, a lot of other things that can be done, but I need some type of starting point, because
Krish NAik: For the next cohort and few other things that, I will be changing the syllabus a little bit of…
Krish NAik: 5% to 10% of reinforcement learning that I'm planning to add it.
Krish NAik: So that's why I'm just looking into the response from you students, because I know that right now, majorly, the crowd who wants to left, they have already left. Only, like, 50 to 60 folks are there who are, like, interested in doing this. I'm just asking for you students only.
Krish NAik: Yes, then explore this. That's why I'm sharing the detailed link also. You can look into.
Krish NAik: I think this is hosted in, like, a University of, Washington.
Krish NAik: Okay, so from that, particular thing only, I've taken this, and based on that…
Krish NAik: Contextual MEBs, yes.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, the things that are remaining, because I think next week I'll be back in Mainland. Okay, so I'll be… I will start taking…
Krish NAik: I think at least 3 extra classes that I'm planning.
Krish NAik: In this, because few things which are out of this syllabus, I want to focus on that. One is that vector-less rat from Page Index. It's, bit, I can say, trending now in the market.
Krish NAik: Okay, but again, like, it's not, like, totally open source, but we'll be going ahead with a version of that, and then we'll be exploring.
Krish NAik: Whether the salary range? We'll say, like, max 35 for it, I don't know
Krish NAik: It depends, like, what is your past in… if you are working, like, 5 to 6 years in the AI domain, Rajat, it can be much harder.
Krish NAik: Because the Geo division has done a tie-up with the NVIDIA, GEO and NVIDIA. So actually, like, Geo is hiring, but he'll be working for NVIDIA. They are paying really good high packages for their R&D division in Chandigar.
Krish NAik: It's not a job, they will be in Chandigarh, but they are actually paying in really good 80 EPA for 6, 7…
Krish NAik: Just, when you have investment, you know what happens. Money…
Krish NAik: like this. Later on, doesn't matter, after 2 years, they will keep you or not, but I know that at least. So, it gives you a good point. So, always look into the organizations who has received funding. The chance of getting much higher package is much easier, I can say, as compared to directly getting somewhere.
Krish NAik: Which is, like, a big organization, having a lot of employees there, it's a bit harder, so…
Krish NAik: Where recently, in the past 1 month or 2 months, they have received investment, probably they are likely to spend much more. But the work will be much better, the quality of the work you're learning, less work-life balance stuff.
Krish NAik: But at least anybody with 5 years of experience, I think they can do it, for probably… because your thing is, you are not looking for stability.
Krish NAik: After 10 years or 15 years, you might be looking for stability, but now, here, simply, you can switch from one orc to one orc.
Krish NAik: Interface integrations, all right. Focus on applications and also then…
Krish NAik: But less hands-on, the classroom has been unable to spend the proceed to learning CQ portion. It's coming in at capstone phase already.
Krish NAik: Hmm…
Krish NAik: There are many. Right now, I'm talking about in India, like, directly, like, Indian companies only, if I… How many of you know about GCCs in India?
Krish NAik: GCC's… Anybody know the initiatives, the global capability centers, the GCSs? Yes.
Krish NAik: These are the silent, guys who doesn't say anything. GCC is okay. And majorly, the GCCs are hiring for quantum-based roles. Not for AI and stuff, they are actually focused on quantum, what is going to happen in the next
Krish NAik: 5 years. Majorly, if you look into their JDs, it's highly statistics, mathematics, they are hiring, and you should be from an AI background, that is the bare minimum, but
Krish NAik: a little bit much more focused on mathematics and statistics. So, I know that the GCC guys are hiring, but if you look into the JD, it's simply, they will state statistician, mathematician, like this.
Krish NAik: Okay, with that, they will say the complete stack up, like, your, LLM will come, your reinforcement learning will come, everything, they will put it in one shot. So, I know that one guy can never know that.
Krish NAik: 50-50 thinking. So I know that later on, the somehow division will be there. In India, the hiring for GCCs are high, but, if you look into the roles, you will feel that it's very much academic roles, lesser from that. But, you know, they are getting paid a lot.
Krish NAik: But also, GCCs in India, it's increasing, so I can say that, yes.
Krish NAik: Once global capability centers are there, they are getting a lot of investment from U.S.
Krish NAik: I, really, like, division models, I prefer, because
Krish NAik: Any models which starts from zero is my preference, whereas any type, like LLMs, if you are working with, they never start from zero.
Krish NAik: Diffusions I love, because in diffusions, everything, you start from nothing, and then you try to build. But it's a very, very long process.
Krish NAik: That's the major, thing. So, couple really, like, I love deficient models, but they are very much compute-hungry.
Krish NAik: It's hardcore mathematics, yes. Actually, that little bit of mathematics is required, because the Indian market is good, but really, identification of the rule that matters.
Krish NAik: Because I know that, two or three, students from ILCP, PhD guys, they got into the GCCs, and they have picked from their master's division in a…
Krish NAik: Iisa Bangalore.
Krish NAik: Okay, a few things. So, majorly, like, IITs and those guys are actually going much more towards GCCs, because the pay is good, very good work-life balance, I can say. And majorly, all the GCCs are highly invested by all U.S. giants.
Krish NAik: Manufacturing giants are investing a lot.
Krish NAik: Alright guys, so now coming to the next part, because next week I'll be doing the release. Now, just tell me that, third and fourth notebook, how many of you have executed?
Krish NAik: Because finally it's done, then I'll be concluding, because in today's session, I don't want to take anything. Most of the content is already there. It's pretty much, like, you have to do the exploitation, because I have already taught you the core functionalities. Now it's you that you'll be doing.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Do Indian markets really look into the fundamentals of LLM? Yes, if you look into… how many of you have looked into the architecture of sarvam?
Krish NAik: Serum AI, yes? So what they have done?
Krish NAik: Grouped query attention they have brought for their smaller model.
Krish NAik: Simply, like, see, simply, like, Indian guys, I can understand. Copy-paste, I can, okay. But fine, they have taken, for their smaller model, they have picked up, group query attention, and for their bigger model, they have taken the deep-seek one, which is MLHN.
Krish NAik: multi-lated head retention. That's the main thing in their transformers model. So, for sure, the performance will be too deep-seek level.
Krish NAik: Okay. Now, if you really have looked into the architecture, these two are the main things. Otherwise, in Indian models, I could not see anything new. So, for sure, they're performing good, but I really, I know, with respect to time, they will degrade, because it's somehow, first copy, I can say.
Krish NAik: Because the core fundamental with respect to the transformer architecture was highly inspired by DeepSea code.
Krish NAik: So that's why I'm telling you two things. In their smaller model, they use GQUA, and in their larger model that they have picked up, which is MLHN.
Krish NAik: Yes, now, that's the thing, who actually changes that, architecture much more? GQN, MLHA, these have been standards in 2025. It's not new in 2026.
Krish NAik: So…
Krish NAik: Yes, like, I know a little bit of copy-paste has to be there. Like, uniqueness, I can say, but that uniqueness doesn't really justify if you are spending a lot on your research.
Krish NAik: Alright, so, guys, next week's agenda will be multimodal. I will start with multimodal, and let me see, because for metadata enrichment, I need only 1 hour. Okay, because I already, I have the Ripper with me. I think, downloads…
Krish NAik: That repo, I'll be pushing. In the meantime, you can actually look into that.
Krish NAik: electronic problem.
Krish NAik: The Deepstick dockling is there, okay.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is another requirement, was there multi-tenant drag.
Krish NAik: Okay, there are two architectures with respect to the tenant, which I have done the implementation with Quadrant. If somebody is interested, this is just tenant, it means that do you have a requirement of multi-collection? Or inside a single collection, you'll be applying it through a filter.
Krish NAik: Okay, now that implementation is there, only that multi-tenant part, because somebody asked me, actually, to do it, and later on, I have done it.
Krish NAik: I have not created the syllabus, let me just go to Bangalore, I will spend 3 to 4 days, and then I will let you know. First of all, the advanced syllabus, I will let you know. RAG 2.0, I will be launching it later on, in the month of July or August.
Krish NAik: Okay, because I don't have normal slots with me now.
Krish NAik: Okay, because first, Sunny's batch, as it's coming, that one, then Mike's batch will come, then my slot will come. Okay, so… but the advanced batch, it will be in the morning batch, morning 5, like, 6 AM, I'm planning for US students, majorly. Okay, so that batch syllabus, I will let you know by, I think, third week of March or second week.
Krish NAik: Now, you can check the Krishnag.in, the new syllabus, and I think, somebody was asking in the chat, like, what are the things?
Krish NAik: Because, rack part also…
Krish NAik: I can discuss that. How many of you know about PromptGuard? Anybody else used PromptGuard?
Krish NAik: I guess?
Krish NAik: Prompt guard, please let me know.
Krish NAik: thought guard, prompt guard, so many things, right? In your batch, who was asking?
Krish NAik: I think Raghavendra was there, yes.
Krish NAik: Now, I'm just showing you, so before taking up any course, just look into, like, how many modules are pretty much unknown to you.
Krish NAik: Good.
Krish NAik: I think next week this batch will start.
Krish NAik: I think which one? Live one.
Krish NAik: Mmm, this is the one. Here, it's a, like, everything it has.
Krish NAik: But, like,
Krish NAik: Because I will be working on the new syllabus, and this is good for anyone who is not totally into that AI stuff, they are somewhere new. I feel that it's good, but again.
Krish NAik: Like, totally, like, how many modules are not known to you. Based on that, you can… I'm sharing the link, you can have a look into the syllabus.
Krish NAik: Yeah.
Krish NAik: Mmm.
Krish NAik: So this is a good starting point. This is a starter. If you're starting at any point of time, this is really a good course. It will give you the fundamentals. Very good fundamentals. But after that, the next level that I will be now planning right now.
Krish NAik: This will be 5 to 6 months, simply you can take it. This is at night, I think, around 8.
Krish NAik: Because my 8th class will be completed, I think, by this month, or April first week, after that. So here, if you have really worked… how many of you have worked with LoRa, QLoRa.
Krish NAik: This one.
Krish NAik: Because, here a few things will be there.
Krish NAik: Now, also, like, if you have not worked with fine-tuning, then, like, it can be a little bit helpful to you.
Krish NAik: But again, you have to understand, if so many things are being taught in 5 months, it becomes very, very hard to just to focus on one stuff, okay? So here, like, agentic AI is there. Like, again, Agent Kai course will come, because… but here, again, only Langraph thing that has been focused a lot.
Krish NAik: Okay? So that's why, like, everything is a bit different. And even I want to talk about that same catcher. Please, give me a…
Krish NAik: reminder by next week that I have taught you Redis, but I want to teach you that Stem Catcher. There is a package actually called as GPT Catcher.
Krish NAik: So, anybody has used that one?
Krish NAik: JPT Azure from Zales, yes?
Krish NAik: This is for building your semantic catcher LLM queries. This demo also, like, I prefer a combination of both, like, one is your main query. With that, you add semantic queries also.
Krish NAik: So in that way, the system becomes somehow a bit cheaper.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, what happens in the Redis? A single keyword changes, again, it will be logged on. So, but here, GPT Catcher actually handles that. So, this part, just remember that I have planned it, but I'm not writing it in my notes, so give me a reminder on that.
Krish NAik: These are very, very small topics, like 15 to 20 minutes only, with respect to that implementation.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, but, remember these things, because later on I can add it.
Krish NAik: Perfect. GPT catcher, read the docs.
Krish NAik: Huh.
Krish NAik: Because so many small, small topics are there, but, like, let's see, like, what are the things we can do.
Krish NAik: Where to add? Amar, you were telling, please add me there. Where should I add you?
Krish NAik: Viraj, AWS RAT platform, okay? I have start implementing branches and features, let me know.
Krish NAik: Alright, let me just check.
Krish NAik: Feature, CDG info, project setup, alright, fine, yes.
Krish NAik: Yes, at least this is a better one, I can say.
Krish NAik: At least, okay? Find at least two branches you have started to work. It's good.
Krish NAik: through PRs, I can see. This is somehow better, I can say.
Krish NAik: Okay, yes.
Krish NAik: Like, if you have a good plan, right now I feel that in today's time, you need to spend more time on the plan. If you're working with any tools, whether root code, Cloud Code, Codex, Drawit, everywhere you need to work on your plan.
Krish NAik: Okay, the more time you spend on your plan, the lesser time you need to actually work on fixing things.
Krish NAik: So, the plan, if it's good, and always try to maintain a list of phase-wise with to-dos. It's very, very important, or a separate file, just to maintain that. Because I feel that the new version of Cloud Code, okay, they spend more and more tokens somehow.
Krish NAik: It means that whenever I use skills, okay.
Krish NAik: with skills, I feel that, yes, they are using more and more tokens.
Krish NAik: Which, previously, it was at least lesser for a few of the things, but this time, really, the consumption of tokens, they have increased it, really. And you have to understand that, whenever they are… if somebody is making the context window bigger and bigger.
Krish NAik: what happens? Can I say that it's a beneficial to the organization? Because those guys will actually keep using those contextual windows.
Krish NAik: It means a certain thing, they will always put it. If it will be smaller, then actually they will do more optimization. But if the window is getting bigger and bigger, let's try to put stuff and put stuff.
Krish NAik: That's what I mean, and now, really, like, Claude does a lot of things there. So that's why more token consumption, more spending. So automatically, that's, like, 1 million tokens, close tokens, like, $5.
Krish NAik: The costliest one.
Krish NAik: That's why… that is the other point where I feel that
Krish NAik: Having a very big context window
Krish NAik: Like, for organization, it's really, really good. They will earn more money.
Krish NAik: So that's why the concept of, that, is coming… allocation, of context window, like, for what type of task, how much you want to allocate. Those things, those concepts are much more coming now.
Krish NAik: Utilization of CN.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Don't create WhatsApp groups. See, later on, once the batch is done, then what happens, actually? WhatsApp group is not a problem for me later on.
Krish NAik: it becomes a problem. So, after that, because I want, like, few people to stay connected, but later on, I will do that. Because, Kresh has really, like,
Krish NAik: And the other team has suffered because of WhatsApp groups.
Krish NAik: Okay. Like, one is a problem, and that problem to become an issue is a very short time that used to happen. So, like, generally we keep the chats closed also. Today, I've opened it, but also I'm, like.
Krish NAik: A small thing, later on, if it becomes an issue, it becomes a problem.
Krish NAik: Cool.
Krish NAik: Are you taking the class which is starting? No, no, I am not there. Because, see, my slots are pretty much booked.
Krish NAik: I… once your batch is done, I'll be taking one month gap. In that one month gap, if I want to take something extra in your batch.
Krish NAik: I won't be taking webinars, I can take, like, one-hour, one-hour sessions, because I'll be traveling in other countries, so, like, one one-hour sessions that I can simply discuss with respect to, RAG stuff. It can be from security perspective.
Krish NAik: Guard railing, a lot of things are there.
Krish NAik: Because the security of,
Krish NAik: those things, like, one hour, those won't be, like, classes you have to understand, because those can be simple sessions that I take it. Once a week, like, one hour, I'll be just showing you a few architectures and a few those things, and you guys can adopt it.
Krish NAik: those things. If you want, I can plan that way.
Krish NAik: Because sitting for 3 hours won't be possible, okay? But if you want, I can plan that. The list of sessions, I can share you by April 1st week.
Krish NAik: Currently working on the automotive domain. Automotive domain has also, like, I know people in the automotive space, Nagash.
Krish NAik: In India, in the automotive space, for AI-based work, you have to be good in vision. Vision-based work is highly there. In India.
Krish NAik: organizations are there. For example, Robert Bosch.
Krish NAik: Okay, there has their multimedia division, which, the multimedia division, the vision division, they actually work, but it's not only text, because for them, images matter much more, you have to understand. So, Nagesh, you need to explore that area, because I know people from that…
Krish NAik: I'm a multimedia, domain who actually uses a lot of camera inputs, and based on that, okay.
Krish NAik: Telematics, yes.
Krish NAik: So, you have to understand for which division. Now, the things that we are dealing here, it's much more from text. And always understand, in a car-based system, nobody will be using LLM, so there, it has to be very, very lightweight. So, probably CNN models are much better there.
Krish NAik: Hold it on… Good.
Krish NAik: Alright, Amar, drop me a mail. I will be sharing you the calendar link, okay, and there you can do it.
Krish NAik: Alright, so I think next week I'll be in Monday, I'll be in better, at least, because… Okay, then, let's discuss, because if you want, in the month of April, I can do it, because I had a plan, a rough estimated one.
Krish NAik: For batch planning also, I need at least from your batch and from the other batch, I will be taking around. Like, same 30 students, they can pass their input. I will be taking 2 to 3 sessions.
Krish NAik: And I'll be giving you the PDFs of all the current, so, like, 50-60% syllabus from my side, and 40% I can take from your side. Okay, so US students, they can give their input, because as that will be a morning batch. Morning 6 that I am planning.
Krish NAik: Because I have another badge that will come to me around the month of August or September, which is that UDS. Okay, so I cannot extend that, so I have to keep it in the morning only.
Krish NAik: My email ID, APPART Krishna, always remember, it's a Notion, everybody.
Krish NAik: Okay. Which batch? I am planning for that, don't worry, I will tell you the plan.
Krish NAik: Once I have that.
Krish NAik: So…
Krish NAik: Just wait, I think I was creating the plan, but again, it's not finalized, but, video just wait. Screen, I think this is desktop 2.
Krish NAik: This is…
Krish NAik: One is at batch completion, this one is…
Krish NAik: I think this is for aggregation, because, this is a rough estimated plan. Okay, but again,
Krish NAik: Not exactly.
Krish NAik: Okay, because the advanced syllabus, I have kept it in the month of…
Krish NAik: 1, 2, 3, 4, 5. So, probably in the month of May only, it is clear. Okay, this is a rough estimated one, but again, I have not finalized it. This plan, I will update you. So, according to your project, when…
Krish NAik: Most of the things, like, will be done.
Krish NAik: Okay, so rough estimations that I have taken.
Krish NAik: Yes, I have actually asked for the resumes, okay? But, again, that resume stuff that I feel that… because I don't have a list. I have few candidates, but again, that hiding their personal information is the biggest pain point whenever I share resume.
Krish NAik: That part, I will do it, okay? Now, let me just unmute a few people.
Krish NAik: They have raised their hands.
Krish NAik: Rajat, MS, okay, everybody I have unmuted.
Murtuza Saifee: Hi, Paul.
Krish NAik: Yes.
Murtuza Saifee: Can I go ahead.
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, please go ahead.
Murtuza Saifee: Thanks, thanks for the session. So, actually, two things. So, first, I will start with my, query. So, actually, I'm…
Murtuza Saifee: designing our RAC solution. In that one, basically, it's document heavy, so what we need to do is, whenever we give that, result to the user in the conversational challenge, in the conversational channel.
Murtuza Saifee: So, we need to attach the lineage. So, what is the source that this information has been extracted out? So, we need… so that the documentation, and which part of the documentation is referred in that response, so that the groundness will come on that. So…
Murtuza Saifee: in the page-level chunking, it's easy so that I can, you know.
Murtuza Saifee: In the metadata, I can attach the page numbers and all those things.
Murtuza Saifee: But if I will go with block-level chunking or, you know, semantic chunking, so I'm just struggling on that piece, so how I will be able to…
Murtuza Saifee: Give that citation or that lineage.
Murtuza Saifee: Of the sources in the response.
Krish NAik: Actually, like, the metadata module, you can keep it separate. See, I'm not mixing metadata with chunking. Let's keep chunking separate. It's not like that, if you are applying, it can be any type of chunking, but your metadata generation to maintain your page numbers and other things, that is separate.
Krish NAik: So I'm not… understanding, like, why you are mixing two things. Because your metadata generation, for every chunk.
Krish NAik: Okay, now that is different. Now, you are telling that, okay, according to your chunking, if you move to semantic chunking, if I take, for example, like, block-level semantic chunking, if you're doing… now, that information will be there, no, during metadata also, when you are actually doing the extraction through page numbers.
Krish NAik: Or anything, line numbers also, you can do it. Okay.
Krish NAik: Exactly. That also you can keep a track.
Murtuza Saifee: But that… but then in… so when I will be, let's say… so let's say there will be a 500-page document, okay? So, out of 500-page document, when the user asks the question, so that information that LLM has… during the retrieval, and then the final response that LLM has generated.
Murtuza Saifee: That response came from the page number 389, let's say.
Murtuza Saifee: So that source, I need to cite it in that conversation, that this conversation or this response has been referred from this section of the document, or let's say this section of multiple documents.
Krish NAik: Alright, I got your point. So simply, like, say, in simple terms, right now, this section, when you say, for example, if you're heading, it becomes, like, harder for me, rather than if you say page number.
Krish NAik: Here, page number becomes easier for me. Otherwise, with every header, you need to attach some type of other data that you can track through. Page numbers are easy to track here.
Krish NAik: Exactly, if you ask me that if this is the heading, if you're looking for H1, H2, or H3 in that way, because for that, then I need to have a separate list that, in these pages, these are the total headers. Now, that mapping needs to be done.
Krish NAik: There's either.
Murtuza Saifee: Along with that.
Murtuza Saifee: Because the requirement is one more, like, allow… so let's say if you, give that page lineage or citations, right?
Murtuza Saifee: So, whenever the user clicks on that source, it opens that 500-page document, and that highlights that, okay, this is the source that has been taken into the consideration of that response generation.
Krish NAik: See, that is somehow at least easy, I can say. For example, whenever you are giving your main response, so you will be having your main retrieve chunks.
Krish NAik: Okay, now from that chunk information, you can actually go back to your original document.
Krish NAik: If you are saving… now, see, generally what happens? Now, if you have telling… you are having a 500-page document, so going back to the document is easy. Now, you need to go exactly, like, in which part of the document you are having that exact information.
Krish NAik: Now, this can be only accessed through metadata only. Now, in the metadata, for example, like, your page number you are keeping, but
Krish NAik: And…
Krish NAik: Because now, like, the program that you are building, like, through that, if you're applying a direct search-based operation, and if you want to show that in UI-based, in backend, it is possible, but
Krish NAik: through a direct search, you can actually get to that exact piece of text also. But, directly through CLI-based approach, you can take the user to that document, prompt that document to that page.
Krish NAik: But after that page, I'm not getting, like,
Krish NAik: this is the exact heading under which. Now, that becomes harder. To do that.
Krish NAik: Page to heading mapping, I need to do it separately.
Krish NAik: through that mapping only, I can access that this page has this particular heading, or some way I need to maintain a TOC that, okay, these are the heading mapping through that. Then only it becomes easier. Otherwise, there is no other way to do and get back to the exact
Krish NAik: Like, this is part of this particular paragraph.
Murtuza Saifee: Because the scale is big, so it's actually a production-level use case, and there are… initially, the PO… for the POC, we need to consider around 10,000 documents. So, with, the different banks…
Krish NAik: Because try to apply the logic for at least, like, before going to 500, test it with a 10-page document, whether that… because I know that, it is possible, but you need to maintain a separate mapping based on your page number to that. So it will be just like.
Murtuza Saifee: I think the metadata and mapping will be very important in.
Krish NAik: metadata, but I… if you feel that you need to keep it in the metadata, or probably for that, I can use something, a lightweight database also. In that database, for that document, if you have 5,000 pages, it will be very, very long, no?
Krish NAik: So that particular information, I don't feel that I will be keeping in the metatria. Rather than in some very lightweight database, I will prefer much.
Krish NAik: Because that is document-level information.
Krish NAik: which is not required, because he'll be actually creating a big mapping, so that mapping entirely byte is required. It's better to go with a SQL-based approach.
Murtuza Saifee: Okay, I will… I will try some of the other approaches, I will let you know.
Murtuza Saifee: So, regarding the second query, so regarding that, timing of the advanced batch you were saying about early 6, so can it be possible to have it, let's say, 7 or 8 India time? Because.
Krish NAik: I can't do it.
Krish NAik: The main problem is, like, in the month of…
Krish NAik: Let's take August or September.
Krish NAik: The other batch is coming, which is right now 9 o'clock. There, I have to teach deep learning. That's the main problem, no? Because that get coincide. I can make that batch, like, it starts from 9, I can tell the students I can make it 9.30.
Krish NAik: But, you have to understand, I cannot make a lot of,
Murtuza Saifee: 6 will be, like, 4.30 for me.
Krish NAik: Okay, like, let's see, because I know that… because, see, for US students, I know that 6 or 6, that is good.
Krish NAik: But, let me see. Then, probably, rather than going for a 3-hour session, we can go for a 2-hour session. Because now it will be less.
Murtuza Saifee: 7, if possible.
Krish NAik: the crowd will be less, the pricing will be high, so I know the crowd will be less. So we can take that decision, because that will be one-to-one. Even 100 students I am taking, I'll be doing a one-to-one, because the expectation for that should be clear.
Krish NAik: Before enrolling, exactly what you are doing, because if I feel that if I'm keeping $300 or $400 for that course, you need to spend from your side at least $100 or $200 to do the practicals.
Krish NAik: Other than we If I ask you to train your own GPT.
Krish NAik: to train your own GPT, the minimum spent according to that, for example, if I go with a nano GPT or a time GPT version, with an A task that, at least if you do the fine-tuning once, it will be around roughly
Krish NAik: $100.
Krish NAik: Okay, the main idea is that's why, it's something not for everyone.
Krish NAik: It's only for a specific who want to do that, it's purely, like, R&D things that I'll be picking up. Much lesser on the applied side, much more on the R&D side, so that at least, if you have never done it in your life, at least you should do it.
Murtuza Saifee: Definitely. No, no, that will be creative, actually.
Krish NAik: And I… I will prefer people using their organization resources, at least try to do it. Don't spend your own money, because every organization allocates that for R&D, you can use stuff. I know that if you're spending $100.
Murtuza Saifee: Yeah, exactly.
Krish NAik: If you're spending $10,000, it can be a big deal in your org. But $100 is fine. For a generic R&D stop, everybody spends
Krish NAik: That is a common amount.
Murtuza Saifee: Yeah, that can be… that can be done, so… Yes. Expenses, clean, everything.
Krish NAik: at an architect level, simply, he or she, nobody asks the question. That's why the purpose is not to take freshers there.
Krish NAik: Because my target will be, at least in Indian audience, like, people who are having 20-25 lakhs package, their package, it should be go on at least, like, that 50 lakhs, 60 lakhs, because I'll be taking a few things only from NVIDIA perspective.
Krish NAik: Okay, like, NIM, okay, highly focusing on inferencing, like, for inferencing, what are the things that needs to be done in quantization, okay, APTQ, those type of things. So, purely technical stuff. It's, and now how we want to do that in your organization, that you guys need to play.
Murtuza Saifee: Yeah, and just to add, so I actually… I think I have been in contact with you and the courses for more than a year now. It helped me a lot, so I have some good news to share with you. I will share with you personally.
Krish NAik: Perfect, fine.
Krish NAik: Thanks, Bob. Okay, so…
Rajat Khanna: Fabulous.
Krish NAik: drop me a mail, then I can share you my number, don't worry.
Krish NAik: People with the jobs, I will say this is really, really a good time. Start applying.
Rajat Khanna: Everybody is getting very good packages, so… And I want to start.
Krish NAik: This is really a good one, I can say.
Krish NAik: Even, like, Krish is shocked, I am shocked. The market is… people are telling no jobs, no jobs, but actually a lot of jobs. Yes, the class is finished, if you want to drop, you can drop.
Krish NAik: Montessor…
Rajat Khanna: Thank you.
Krish NAik: So, yes, Raja, you want to share? Alright.
Rajat Khanna: No, no, share, share as in, share as in my, my, the thing that I want to share with you, not the screen share.
Krish NAik: Okay, okay, fine.
Krish NAik: proceed.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, so, the first thing is, like, as you told, like, the market is really great for the March and April month. So, how long our course is going to be? How long, I think, it will push to April and May month?
Krish NAik: Not April. By April, things will be done. Second week, I told.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, and, the second thing is, like, so the agentic-based, system, like, the agentic-based classes, when that will start?
Krish NAik: Agentic-based classes.
Rajat Khanna: Agenda, like, you will be… you told na, you will share one… one project or, the classes related.
Krish NAik: The last project, the fifth project, it will be based on Agentech, RAG.
Rajat Khanna: And, which we are using, like, Llama, like, Llama Index, or Crew AI, what…
Krish NAik: No, no, no, no, no, not Llama Index. Like, I can use, but I was planning to build the entire agent
Krish NAik: See, there are two ways. I can build the entire Agentic framework by myself. I was planning to focus on FS file-based systems.
Krish NAik: Much more, it means that the agent that you'll be building, it will be having access to your local file system.
Krish NAik: It means that I'll be building commands for executing GREP, for any type of thing, WC3, so that it can analyze, for example, if it want to access any type of PDF files, if you want to read. So for that, the local system package, that is the project. It's something like a high-level data implant.
Krish NAik: Not the other way around, like directly going through Langraph and other. That is much easier, and there are much more resources, but for local file-based systems approaches, I can say lesser resources, something… and very high abstraction level of, like, Cloud Code, Droid, where actually it can. You give the agents access to your local system.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, and, related to the organization's perspective, like, in the big organization, so they are using the framework-based agent systems, or any other approach, like, in the organization?
Krish NAik: Last year, people have been doing that only. Now they are moving toward local build.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, okay, now you're saying…
Krish NAik: The shift has been there. No, that's why, like, this, Claude Coo work and other things, they are getting much more famous.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, okay. And, just to, just as I shared, like, I'm giving the interviews and all those things.
Rajat Khanna: So, like, I have knowledge of this particular course that you are teaching into, so do I need to be more exploring into other, like, the second course that you will be building on, basically on RAG?
Krish NAik: Second course, see, second course will be a little bit different. I'll be telling you about that, because till now, the plan is not finalized, what are the topics.
Krish NAik: And other things. But I can say it will be much more R&D perspective. It means, let's see, one thing, if you enroll in the course, you see stuff. That doesn't make sense.
Krish NAik: If I share something, you need good info. It means that I'm talking about you need A100s and H100s to do execution. Now, those GPUs per hour, it will be costing around $3 to $4.
Krish NAik: So at least, if you're doing for any task for 6 hours or 7 hours, at least if you don't want to do it, I will be doing it, so I know that I'll be spending. Otherwise, you can just watch it like a movie. Okay, yes, this is done, and this is the output.
Krish NAik: There are two ways, simply. So, it is much more practical-focused. It means that, it is highly, like, I can say that
Krish NAik: resource and tensor. I'll be spending more on, because the idea is to move from this enterprise stuff, like OpenAI and other things, and focusing much more on data-specific SLMs. It means that I'll be building my own language model according to my own enterprise data.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, okay, okay. So, like, those solutions are also being used to a normal mid-range organization, mid-range, I would say, like.
Krish NAik: Building SLMs.
Rajat Khanna: important call.
Krish NAik: everybody is preferring them. Why they will… just think about why I will pay money to OpenAI for next… if the project is going for 5 years. Do you think that…
Rajat Khanna: Okay.
Krish NAik: It doesn't make sense. Initially, fine, but later on, later on, once you have… see, initially, I start the project, I will be having less data.
Krish NAik: soon I'm, open it to the public, or the end users start using it, I will be having more and more data. Once I have more and more data, I can say that, yes, I can plan for an SLM.
Rajat Khanna: But for, like, just to have a question in my mind, so we have Ollama-based systems, like, we can buy a local LLM model, and then we can use in the,
Krish NAik: Yes.
Rajat Khanna: solutions. So, those are also cheap options available.
Krish NAik: Those are cheap options, but are those LLMs are specifically for your data.
Rajat Khanna: Okay.
Rajat Khanna: Correct.
Rajat Khanna: But for our kind of data research, same, like, RAG is… RAG is there for the architectural purpose, like, we are using OLAMA-based local LLMs, and then we are providing our own data on top of it to generate specific answers.
Krish NAik: Yes, I will say, because… again, repeat what you told.
Rajat Khanna: So, you are saying, like, we are creating our own large language model based on our own data, so those,
Krish NAik: I won't be creating large language models. I will be picking up something around 7 billion, 2 billion, those type of models that I want to fine-tune.
Krish NAik: Large language models I can do, it is not possible only. Yes, yes. It is spent a lot. SLMs, I know, with a… at least, because I have to… before that, see, before creating SLMs, I need to teach you how to create synthetic data pairs.
Krish NAik: the data augmentation which is required for fine-tuning, that part I need to focus on. A lot of things that comes, it's not only one thing. Then comes the evaluation of that according to a benchmarking.
Krish NAik: It means the process is really long. It means that for a single practical, probably I need to spend more than 6 to 7 classes.
Rajat Khanna: Yes, and while I was reading more on some… another stuff, so I came to know, like, there are LLM models, and on those LLM models, we can take specific amount of their neural networks, and then use them, rather than using full LLM models. So I didn't get that.
Krish NAik: That is something like, for example, if I pick an… let's not take LLM, okay? Let's pick up something like an SLM, or let's talk about a neural network.
Rajat Khanna: My idea is that I'll be using the architecture.
Krish NAik: Okay, now probably a few layers that I'll be freezing, okay, and those layers, which I'll be, like, in the unfreeze mode, I'll be training them on top of our own data.
Rajat Khanna: Yes, yes, correct, yes.
Krish NAik: That is… this is how simply computer vision works, that is how your NLP works, that is how even here it works. But few things will change, because here, the concept of adapters will come.
Krish NAik: because of that, like, LoRa, QLORA, these are old. Right now, in the market, they are better. Vera, Dora, okay, like, those are much better as compared. LoRa, Q LoRa 2024 stuff. Now, I will be updating those things much more.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, okay, so by April, like, we will be completing this course. So, like, these concepts are… or these learnings are, sufficient enough to, like.
Krish NAik: These learnings are very, very, like, in India, very less people work on this.
Krish NAik: Less people, more money up to understand.
Krish NAik: Okay. It's like, lesser people lose these concepts, and…
Rajat Khanna: This is much more problematic.
Krish NAik: R&D.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, this is…
Krish NAik: Everybody want to be applicable what you are telling?
Rajat Khanna: This RAG course, the RAG course that you… we are doing currently right now.
Krish NAik: generic. Yeah, yeah, yeah. The idea here is keeping it generic, not too much pushing toward the R&D stuff.
Rajat Khanna: Hmm.
Krish NAik: That thing is much more R&D stuff.
Rajat Khanna: So, this is… the question is, like, this is sufficient enough to start our journey and to take these projects.
Krish NAik: This is a starter course, like, if everybody is building a RAG system, this is a good point to start. You get all the fundamentals, from here you can actually move to the next step, at least. Because I feel that, getting the right direction, and I feel that from this course, with respect to building a rag-based systems, you will get a correct direction.
Krish NAik: Now, from this direction, you need to go ahead and spend more on research, and based on that, you can pick it up.
Rajat Khanna: No, no, for the enterprise level, as I told you, like, I started giving interviews, and I will be selecting in few, and might be, like, doing their work, like, enterprise-related work, and all those things. So, these knowledge are sufficient enough to start.
Krish NAik: There is nothing called a sufficient, that is the thing. According to you, and according to me, sufficient… see, sufficient… I can say that… I cannot say it is enough also.
Krish NAik: Okay. I know that, yes, these are the fundamental things that you need if you are working.
Rajat Khanna: Dude.
Krish NAik: ENF means what? According to enough means sabata aka. What is that enough meaning? Because you cannot…
Rajat Khanna: company mein jayinge toh…
Krish NAik: Huh, company.
Rajat Khanna: Thank you, John.
Krish NAik: So, you know the basics. Once you know the basics and the fundamentals, then you will be getting correct instincts. It means that your decision lean out there. Usually, you will be taking at least the correct instinct. I hope you get that.
Rajat Khanna: Hmm, okay.
Krish NAik: Instinct, because for me, anyone, if I am teaching anything, for me, that you should have the fundamentals correct. If your fundamentals are correct, then your instincts are correct.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, if your fundamentals are wrong, then instinct is wrong.
Krish NAik: And if your inject is wrong, it means that aki cheese ko char bar gumah gumag karim.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, okay.
Krish NAik: Pretty? Alright.
Rajat Khanna: That's it. Thank you, thank you, Paul.
Krish NAik: Hmm.
Mudassar Hakim: Keep it on the street. I'll go next.
Krish NAik: If…
Mudassar Hakim: So, Paul, what I was trying to call out in the chat also is, I think there's definitely a bigger forum of folks with 15 years' experience here, which we definitely need some direction. Personally speaking, what I'm trying to do is, I'm trying to project my credentials
Mudassar Hakim: more towards a COE head or a AI transformation lead, and I'm trying to structure my profile more in that area.
Mudassar Hakim: Also, I've been working with the talent team to create a ready set of resources where, you know, we can plug them on opportunities that come around this area.
Mudassar Hakim: And, also…
Krish NAik: Right. Now, for this, because for this, Mayank will be working, because he is planning for a batch.
Krish NAik: For that, leader stuff, I don't know, he will be modifying the last syllabus, he will be bringing some things much more on the cloud, and a few other things, but leader-based batch, he is working, because that is now… because I think last month only Chris took the decision that he will be working on that type of batch.
Krish NAik: Much more.
Krish NAik: Because I'm not picked up for leaders, I have very specifically picked up only the R&D division.
Mudassar Hakim: Right. What I feel is that, I'm not asking that you drive this part.
Mudassar Hakim: What I'm asking is that, can we have some community created in the… in the Grish Academy part? Because I understand I don't want to put you ourselves into a.
Krish NAik: on the, like.
Mudassar Hakim: creating WhatsApp or anything right now, because I think we need some kind of, information flow across the domains, best practices across the domains, because this, I understand.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Mudassar Hakim: The organization will have…
Krish NAik: Actually, there are a few admins in Telegram, okay, because, again, I need to get some admins. I will ask Karish about this, okay, and then, probably, at Telegram, generally, we don't use WhatsApp or Telegram channel that, I think he will be creating, and I think…
Krish NAik: There are a few already available mod guys, moderators are there.
Krish NAik: And then that I have to ask him, drop me a mail, at least to mention this one, so that I can at least forward him, because personally, I will meet him, I think, next week, once I reach Bangalore, but, at least…
Krish NAik: Like, a valid, I need that, okay, now this guy and these guys are actually planning. Okay, that part I want.
Krish NAik: Okay, you can let me know, then, for a Telegram group, I can tell you, because there are certain things for anyone, I can understand the requirement for anywhere above that architect level and directly working with respect to, like, directors and others. Yes, the requirement is a bit different. Totally different, I can say, as you will be handling directly teams and business decisions.
Krish NAik: Fine, you can drop me a mail, and built on that, I can just create that particular group, and I can ask him.
Mudassar Hakim: Sure, sure. So basically, you need just a nail with a
Mudassar Hakim: We need that, you know, we need some cross-information flow across this set of people who are 15 plus experienced, and we need.
Krish NAik: Bartan, as you were telling, can you… in Slack, the problem in the free Slack, whatever the thing is that you do, after 2 weeks, it is gone.
Krish NAik: That's why I don't prefer. If you are having an enterprise lag, it's fine. Then for a user, you are paying. But I don't think it is required in this case, so generally, I prefer Discord much more.
Krish NAik: Or otherwise, if I'm hosting, if anybody has that… what does that matter most, I think? The free alternative of Slack. But again, I need to host it in a certain BPS server just to make that.
Mudassar Hakim: Yeah, I'm fine with any channel, for that matter, but at least some kind of a directional discussion is needed here. And I feel like this is something everywhere, bits and pieces, people are doing it, but we just need some kind of a forum to have a conversation and share those insights.
Mudassar Hakim: And secondly, what my personal experience is, Paul, with respect to these courses, right, the readership courses, even the ISB ones, they are more at a surface level. They don't really talk about,
Mudassar Hakim: primary decision-making criterias. Even today, right, what we are talking about is various
Mudassar Hakim: areas to explore. There is haystack, there is LandChain, there is Llama Index, lot of things, right? But with respect to productionizing, stability, choosing something, and moving ahead, with respect to a short-term project, long-term project, with respect to revenue, with respect to costing.
Mudassar Hakim: resources, that kind of a delivery is not there in the market. That is the main challenge. I checked.
Krish NAik: I got your point, the same thing, like, Raul's wife knew yesterday.
Krish NAik: See, now that requirement is for a very niche crowd.
Krish NAik: Yes, it's a very, very niche requirement. It's something like if somebody here, having 4 years, 5 years, 6 years, even they don't have such a requirement.
Krish NAik: If somebody is more than that 15, so I got your point. Yes, pretty much valid to take proper business decisions, planning a project for a long-term prospect, those… that is a little bit different. So that's why people deal less on those things.
Krish NAik: Okay, and for that part, really, like, even, some plans are there. I know that Mike has, like, he has started working on that, but again, not a lot. So, probably I will ask the team…
Mudassar Hakim: poll, if you just start even a poll, right, I'm pretty sure you'll get proper 50 to 30 folks right now. I think, so the kind of an interaction I'm having daily in our sessions.
Krish NAik: I got your point. Now, that is the main thing, you know. We never target for 20 to 30 folks, you know, that if you look into our pricing…
Mudassar Hakim: That's what I'm thinking, right? It's an incremental approach.
Krish NAik: I got your point, I got your point.
Mudassar Hakim: I understand your audience. You get the quantum of your audience, right, by getting this community created. Once you know the audience, the pain point, then you can go for.
Krish NAik: I got your point, see, I got your point on that one, but you have to understand.
Krish NAik: I, like, from our perspective, what we think, that matters. Like, for me as a mentor, like, now, it becomes a risky part.
Krish NAik: Like, if I am taking some, like, batch, if I'm telling, okay, now, do I want to go with a higher pricing plan, and looking for a niche crowd?
Krish NAik: that becomes, like, majorly, most of the organizations are doing it. In Kresh's case, he doesn't, actually. He tells that we… because our main income comes from other pointers, so he tells don't keep it as a main one.
Krish NAik: keep it as a part-time. Keep it like that. Okay, but specialized means when we charge more.
Krish NAik: Then the expectation is also very, very high.
Krish NAik: Okay, and sometimes, because, if unable to fulfill that bad repo in the market, we don't want. So, Krish, never take that risk only. Keep it generic for generic crowd. I hope you get it, from our perspective.
Mudassar Hakim: onboarded here. I'm not saying to start creating courses here. What I'm saying is, at least initiate a controlled community within… See?
Krish NAik: This year, only, I am the only guy who is willing to take the risk for an higher US badge dedicated lead. Now, the question comes, who is the next C? It's a mentor's choice. Okay, now I am ready to take the risk for that, for an RIT, but every mentor is not willing to take the risk, you have to understand.
Mudassar Hakim: I think so, we are talking about two different things here. I'm not talking about, right now, creating courses.
Krish NAik: No, no, no. See, anything that needs to be delivered, it has to be planned from mentor. Whenever you request anything, anything, you have to understand that.
Krish NAik: If you request me, okay, plan, like, let's take a cohort of 30 students, okay, then let's talk, then somebody has to go into that discussion, take your inputs, plan something.
Mudassar Hakim: No, but I'm not saying that, right? That's what I'm going for. You don't need.
Krish NAik: wrong, right?
Mudassar Hakim: to execution. Start with initiation, where you create a community. Let that cross-domain knowledge discussions happen over there, observe the pain points, see the crowd, getting accumulated.
Krish NAik: Can't do that.
Mudassar Hakim: and then we can have a decisioning. There is a sufficient crowd, it's no longer a niche, now we can talk about creative goals. That is more data-driven decisioning for you guys also, not just with respect to open.
Krish NAik: In this case, nothing, like,
Krish NAik: Kresh, then he will say that, Paul, you only create a dedicated Discord server. You do that, because I don't want to get dealt into…
Mudassar Hakim: delegate it to me.
Krish NAik: He will say, that becomes my main thing. All right, finally, if it's niche crowd, I can create a dedicated server there.
Krish NAik: Okay, because even for your… this project that I was planning.
Mudassar Hakim: Let the… let the.
Krish NAik: Alright, fine.
Mudassar Hakim: What about the button?
Krish NAik: make a poll next week, I will create a Google form. People having more than 10 years of experience, let's put them in one site. Even I will get the data, because here, actually, in that form, I asked for leads, having more than. From there also, let me just filter it out, and then I will do that.
Mudassar Hakim: That's what I was saying, don't jump into creating courses. We can do that at a later part, but first, at least accumulation, initiation, where you get more.
Krish NAik: The all-time data happening, what's… what is the key, what is the change?
Mudassar Hakim: And grow.
Krish NAik: Got to your point, got to your point. I will create it, because, see, then, like, I only have to do that.
Mudassar Hakim: We are here to help you, right, Paul? You may… I understand.
Krish NAik: All right, fine. Yes, yes, I know from that.
Mudassar Hakim: Plus ones and plus twos to drive these better.
Krish NAik: Alright, alright, fine.
Krish NAik: So let me plan next week, I will then do that, and I will let you know.
Mudassar Hakim: Awesome, awesome. Yep, thanks.
Satish: I apologize here.
Soham Dutta: I also have it.
Krish NAik: One by one, yeah.
Krish NAik: Anyone thought they should go ahead first.
Satish: Yes, actually, I want to know about the next batch, which is starting to…
Krish NAik: When I'm planning the syllabus. Till now, it's something like I've broke. I've kept the syllabus, like, fundamental of Transformers. From that Fundamentals, I've kept one part with SLMs, LLMs, RAG, VLLMs.
Krish NAik: And last reinforcement learning. It will be, like, 6-month course that I have planned, but it will be in the morning. These things I have planned till now.
Krish NAik: But exactly what will be there inside the module, I need to work on that. So once I work, let me be in Bangalore by March 3rd week, like, 22nd or 23rd, I'll be working on that, and I'll be sharing.
Krish NAik: Okay. Okay.
Satish: Second question is… huh, second question is, what about that 15 months that course is being started, na? So, any ideas?
Krish NAik: Now, that course, it's something like, in high level, everything. I feel that this is much for a beginner level who has zero idea about Gen AI.
Satish: Okay, so I have a 10-year experience, so I don't think that the course will be, huge for me.
Krish NAik: check out the modules. If you feel just only 3-4 modules are unknown to you, I won't suggest, because
Krish NAik: 3 to 4 modules in today's…
Krish NAik: time, you can do your own research, better to spend that money somewhere, as I know there are better options. So you have to take that decision. If you feel that somebody, karate the khayga, then it becomes easier for me, then fine, you can go. If you feel that lunga, if you have that approach, then that's better, I feel.
Satish: Okay, okay.
Krish NAik: That approach taking part, whether, I will do that, I will handle it.
Satish: Yes, yes. Okay, okay. Thank you.
Ishan Pande: Hey, hi Bob, Jacob.
Krish NAik: Yes.
Ishan Pande: So, Paul, I'm… currently, I'm working on two, three projects in my organization. So, one of the questions which always gets asked to me is, like.
Ishan Pande: how you will measure the productivity we are achieving through these AI products. For example, let's say I'm developing an agent which is generating code, let's say, okay?
Ishan Pande: So… so do you have any, thoughts on this? Like, how do we measure the productivity which we would be achieving through these agents or these agent API platforms? For example, I'm generating some lines of code, some lines of…
Krish NAik: Nope.
Ishan Pande: test groups, yeah.
Krish NAik: Let's see, productivity, you say it's a very high-level word.
Krish NAik: Now, before productivity, now, you have to define productivity based on what? What are those metrics that you are planning?
Ishan Pande: Hmm.
Krish NAik: It means that the evaluation of the responses from the agents, that needs to be measured. That is step one.
Krish NAik: Okay, now it can be based on latency, it can be based on quality, so a lot of things that comes into the picture. Now, when you say directly productivity, it's a very high level word. Now, the productivity needs to be broken down into actual, like, quantitative metrics, I can say, at least.
Ishan Pande: So let me give you…
Krish NAik: Hmm.
Ishan Pande: Sorry, let me give you an example. Let's say, based on the requirement, I'm generating an automation test scripts, okay, with the help of Selenium REST Azure. Let's assume this.
Ishan Pande: Now, I already have a repository where, let's say, 50 plus test scripts were automated. Now, with the help of this agent DKI platform, let's say I have generated 20 plus scripts, and then I have merged that into the repository.
Ishan Pande: Now, one of the, one of the problems we face here is, like, how do I detect what… what percent of the code was written with AI2?
Krish NAik: what percentage of the code was written with the AI?
Ishan Pande: Nothing.
Krish NAik: your existing code, and where you are merging that code. So, probably, and through a git diff, you can.
Satish: Meh!
Krish NAik: Atish, just beyond… Oh, yes.
Jatinder Bali: So, sorry, Paul, can I answer that?
Krish NAik: If you don't mind? Yeah, yeah. Yeah, yeah.
Jatinder Bali: Okay, so… so I think, so there are many, many, points, right? One is obviously your velocity in your sprint.
Ishan Pande: Yeah, you can measure with that, but I think you're more specifically asking…
Jatinder Bali: You know, you ever heard of SonarCube?
Ishan Pande: Yes, sir.
Krish NAik: So now you can detect, right? It can… it has got modules that can detect whether it's written by AI, whether it's written by…
Jatinder Bali: By human.
Jatinder Bali: So, you can use that to distinguish your, your percentage of your…
Jatinder Bali: So what we have done in our organization is, we have a… if you have a PR opened up.
Jatinder Bali: That PR is… you can say who that person is.
Jatinder Bali: So you can say, now you can even do add Claude. You say Add Claude, and Claude will work on that PR.
Jatinder Bali: So you know end-to-end, that whole thing is developed by Claude, and you slowly pointed that PR.
Jatinder Bali: That's how you do it. But whoso is asking this question has got no knowledge of what
Jatinder Bali: what a real, you know, exec is, right? Even in big companies, you know, you're talking about NVIDIA, you're talking about, like, JPMorgan, you're talking about Citi, nobody is measuring ROI on agents right now. Everybody has just got their…
Jatinder Bali: You know, they're just… they're just swimming around, trying to figure out what's going on.
Jatinder Bali: So you should tell them, and there are a lot of studies, right? You can go to universities and figure out what the studies are there, but nobody's doing that. It's…
Jatinder Bali: And the only people who are doing it is, like, these OpenAI and big companies.
Jatinder Bali: So, but SonarCube, and you can probably go to other tools, tools like that, even send them to…
Jatinder Bali: The dashboards, the… Where they are, you know, looking at the agent interactions. You can show them those dashboards.
Jatinder Bali: Thank you.
Ishan Pande: The second follow-up question I have, Molly, like, so, I have been learning a lot around this, how to build your ads, agents, what are different types of frameworks, right?
Ishan Pande: But then, when… when we have to drive certain projects, we have to, you know, write down, documents around, like, what is our strategy, what is our AI strategy to build this product, right?
Ishan Pande: then what is our design? Then, what is your implementation roadmap? Then, what are some of the agent KPIs which we want to track? And then, eventually, like, how much,
Ishan Pande: Dollar saving we would be achieving as a result of this,
Krish NAik: Hold out, okay? Alright, yes, I got it.
Ishan Pande: So, do you have any plans, like, Paul, to show us, like, okay, this was the project, and considering this scope in mind, this is how we have to develop a strategy, and this is how the design document looks like.
Krish NAik: Damn.
Krish NAik: I got your point, so this is a very similar type of requirement as Mudhasar was discussing, okay? Like, KPI-based, business decision-based, time and revenue-based decisions. Okay, now, really, like, not in this batch.
Krish NAik: But probably, because for that, I need a working product. From that working product, I need to pull up the matrix.
Krish NAik: Okay
Krish NAik: like, through a BI tool I need to showcase, it becomes a pain point for me. Okay, now, let me see, from an existing one, probably.
Krish NAik: I can do it, because through Prometheus and Grafana, we have our existing dashboards deriving KPIs, but step one, because I have not planned for that.
Krish NAik: probably, like, you have to keep this in a bucket list, if that requirement. Because, see, to set up the info, it's much easier. But based on that, according to your use case, you need to derive those,
Krish NAik: thing. Because I can help you out, I can show you a few examples, but, later on, through your own dashboard, through your own BI tool, you need to access that information and derive those insights.
Krish NAik: Okay, if you want… now, have you done the setup ever on that?
Krish NAik: The setup, at least.
Ishan Pande: Sure, yeah, let us know whenever you get in.
Krish NAik: Okay, because I will keep it. Let's try to create, because these things, again, very niche requirement, setting up, PROM and these things, I will keep it then, probably. Prometheus and Grafana, I'm not really, like, for dashboarding tools that I prefer, but yes, all right, Modhasa.
Ishan Pande: The next…
Soham Dutta: Paul, so humb this side.
Krish NAik: Yeah, yeah, so I'm good.
Soham Dutta: Well, thank you for your classes, right? I have not been to AI, but it has been quite an extensive journey for me also, right?
Soham Dutta: So thank you for…
Soham Dutta: all the classes that you have taken. So, Paul, there's, there are one or two things that I wanted to, take your opinion about. So, first thing is, Paul, let's say,
Soham Dutta: when you'll be taking the SLM classes, right? So, those SLM classes will, like, how those SLM will be different, like, those are continuation of RAC? Like, how do…
Krish NAik: No, no, no, no, no, no, no, those will be, like, if you… you have to know Transformers. I'll be taking at least a high-level Transformers class.
Soham Dutta: See, like.
Krish NAik: For example, if somebody is from that UDS, like, let's try to break things, like a transformer's encoder-specific, decoder-specific sequences.
Krish NAik: sequence-specific. First, I will give you that idea, then I will come to the types of encoders, like by encoders, cross-encoders, and that way. Okay, then, like, architecture specific, like in DeepSig, this was their… I will give you at least a high-level, holistic overview. Now, this is actually the LLM space.
Krish NAik: Now, from that… because initially, Back in 2019, 2020, we have been working with SLMs.
Krish NAik: having lesser number of params. Now, there we used to call them language models, but.
Soham Dutta: Connecticut.
Krish NAik: the term LLM came, and then very specifically, we were telling SLM, but actually, we have been dealing with SLMs only.
Soham Dutta: Hmm.
Krish NAik: So, it's not possible to deal everyone directly with LLMs, because, very high… So, we'll be talking about those things, like, Lamini and other things, I will give you those examples. And then I'll be picking up… I will be picking up a domain-specific data, then I'll be picking up, for example, like, Liquid AI.
Krish NAik: Right now in the market, it is providing, I can say, the models which are really good.
Soham Dutta: Okay, and there.
Krish NAik: post-training approaches, if you really about, see, because little bit about post-training, these are, like, advanced concepts, but if somebody is really into that, okay, because… just wait, let me just open and show it to you.
Krish NAik: So, Paul, I have a, like, fair bit of knowledge on Transformer, but not as extensive. Don't worry, I will cover that part, no. I know that most of you won't be having that, and you guys need a recap, at least people who have done that. Okay.
Soham Dutta: Also, one year back, I… I followed some short Laby's YouTube video, and I just tried to script everything from end to end, right? Only that knowledge I have, like, it's probably only level one, nothing beyond that.
Krish NAik: Alright, so… just wait, I think I've got this. So, Liquid AI part, I was actually exploring a lot. So, something like this. So, this is a simple block, like, exactly after post-training, what are the things that need to be done according to a hardware, how to handle a particular output.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is actually what is post trading. Many of you might not know about it. Okay, now from post…
Krish NAik: training to fine-tuning how to combine that from 1 million samples to 10. These are the things that I'm planning. Now, which libraries to work with? You have Axotel, Onslaught, okay, now Evaluation. Okay, now comes your supervised fine-tuning. So.
Soham Dutta: Step…
Krish NAik: step by step, like, from a thing, how you get… so these type of things, actually, I was planning to work on much.
Soham Dutta: vote.
Soham Dutta: And when tentative when this class should start?
Krish NAik: It will take time, like, I need at least, 2 months just to work on different type of content only. Of course.
Soham Dutta: After May or June, if it is, then I would be able to happily join it.
Krish NAik: 50 years after… see, in the month of May, like, I will be traveling completely. So, there, this time, I will be taking just one hour discussion in syllabus finalization.
Soham Dutta: Okay.
Krish NAik: like, people who are done there, at least I know people who are taking. So, initially, I'll be taking 20-30 students who are interested, and later on, like, I'll be planning the syllabus 2 months, and probably 3 or 4 students I will pick up who can work on the content with me
Krish NAik: In that way, I will try to do it. It will be totally community-driven and student-driven. It's not like everything I will be doing. I'll be giving you access.
Krish NAik: So at least I'm planning, like, 3 students or 4 students that I will pick up. From this course, there are 2 other courses also that I'm taking from there.
Krish NAik: Okay, so who has time?
Krish NAik: and others. So, little bits, few things that I'll be talking about. Now, these are a little bit advanced up, but I feel that…
Krish NAik: Actually, like, if you want, this is where thing comes.
Soham Dutta: I think it will be interesting also. It will also very core related to DS, pure maths also, whatever you are showing.
Krish NAik: digital signal processing will come. Mathematics, for sure. Without mathematics, nothing can be derived wrong. So, yes.
Soham Dutta: So, also, one more thing, so Paul, like, the Google form that you have floated out last week, right?
Krish NAik: It was such a shit, yeah.
Soham Dutta: Yes, yes, I filled, right? I had one doubt. See, I have… I don't have experience on, any cloud, right?
Soham Dutta: I'm honest, but with you on this, but how do I make sure that this class, like, what is the eligibility criteria for having this.
Krish NAik: Actually, I'm looking for a cloud-specific student, because the projects are cloud-specific, so at least you have to know the services.
Soham Dutta: See, if you don't know, fine, once these guys have done the work, they will showcase the work, then take the inputs.
Krish NAik: See, if somebody knows stuff, it becomes much easier for him to develop it. It means at least he or she will know to AI what is the prompt that needs to be written.
Krish NAik: Okay, now once he or she knows that, I know the development will be faster. Once the development is done entirely, then simply these guys will give you the demo, and they will explain you the project. I will be giving them, like, explain, like, one session or two sessions according to that weekend plan.
Soham Dutta: Okay, okay, fine, fine.
Krish NAik: This will be, like, after completing, because for this project, I will give them at least 45 days, take time. It's not, like, complete live coding within 8 hours, that's not the idea. Take your time, explain, work on the architecture if something that needs to be modified. So, those decisions can be taken. So, I'm taking around at least 45 to 60 days of work.
Krish NAik: So, majorly, right now, it's March, if I say. Next week, if I finalize, March, April, May. So, probably in the month of May for your batch. So that's why I'll be keeping, not webinar, rather than meetings, I'll be keeping. Like, small, small meetings, according to the group.
Krish NAik: So, based on that. And for that, they will be having
Krish NAik: different discords. So, in that way, I'll be taking that community-based approach, right? After the syllabus is done, then also from where you can actually pick up things.
Soham Dutta: Okay, thank you, thank you, Paul. Okay.
Krish NAik: All right.
Jatinder Bali: Hey, Paul.
Krish NAik: Hmm.
Jatinder Bali: Can I go next? Is Jatander?
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, yes, yes, please go ahead.
Jatinder Bali: Okay, so I didn't understand the whole point of that 20 minutes, call with, I don't know, Mudassar, what you're having, okay?
Jatinder Bali: But my question is something different, but but I don't… I agree with you, right? Krishnak is… Krishnak Academy is not for…
Jatinder Bali: You know, it's more for the general public, to…
Krish NAik: You gave…
Jatinder Bali: to be a platform for, you know, 3,000 people, rather than be a platform for 20 people, because if you want to be a platform for 20 people, you need a different set of people, you know, divide the whole org into, you know, two different pieces.
Jatinder Bali: Plus, with the projects that you're doing, those also, you know, pretty… take a lot of time.
Jatinder Bali: So, I think I agree, right? It's, doing… doing that diversification into somebody who is 15 years plus in career, or somebody who is less than 15 is… is gonna be very difficult for Krishnak Academy, right? It will be a lot of…
Jatinder Bali: you know, money is never a problem, I believe. It's always, you know, the time. You can do 10,000 courses in…
Jatinder Bali: You know, online, but it's always a time that you're wasting, and what is the fastest way to get, and mostly the fastest way to get is to experiment, to get your, you know, get your feet in somewhere, and tell… go ask somebody, you know, what's your problem?
Jatinder Bali: Now, that's what I do in my org. Ask somebody, what's your problem? They tell me I have this problem. I say, okay, I'll come back to you.
Jatinder Bali: So, that was my thing, yeah. Maybe… I don't know what angle you're thinking, But.
Krish NAik: your part is correct. See, now I'm ready to… it's a mental choice whether somebody wants to do that. So, that's why I'm planning for that morning. I told you, no. Like, little bit, I can do the testing, let's see, and… because, fine, 6 months, a lot of new things that I'm planning to take it, much more practical-focused stuff.
Krish NAik: A lot of theoretical stuff, but I'm willing to take that chance, because that is actually for a niche crowd. Anybody less than 3 years of experience, I won't be taking them into the course only. But let's see, like, how things go forward. That way, at least I can do the experiment.
Jatinder Bali: So do you work full-time for Krishnak, or you do projects also, you do consulting?
Krish NAik: So you were conflicting company, too? No, no, no, no. Only conflicting that way, because I don't have time. I left the office.
Jatinder Bali: Yeah.
Krish NAik: And now, again, I am planning, because I'm not married till now, so I have lots of time. Okay, now, I don't know in the next one year. If I get married next year, then things will change, that's why.
Krish NAik: Now I'm ready to… willing to take a lot of risk, but let's see what happens. In 2027, the plan is there.
Jatinder Bali: Okay, so my, my actual question was, whenever you do this project, there is, I don't know where, where did that,
Jatinder Bali: And I tried to log in there, the India AICompute.indi.gov.n, right? That is the place where you can get these compute clusters.
Jatinder Bali: What happened to that, website? Is it… is it… have you ever worked on it?
Krish NAik: No, I have not used this one. You shared the link, but the URL is not opening.
Jatinder Bali: So this one, there's another one, let me share another one, right? So this is… this is the actual one where you can go log in and get the…
Jatinder Bali: And the… the compute, so I can…
Jatinder Bali: So this is the, what is it, India AI, right?
Krish NAik: Okay, okay, I got.
Jatinder Bali: Singapore.
Krish NAik: It is. Yes, yes, yes.
Krish NAik: Compute Portal, Apply Now, PhD, Scholar, Startups, MSc.
Krish NAik: I hate…
Jatinder Bali: I'll show you. It's a, if you just go to their India… India, if you… and it's very not very… it's such a big,
Jatinder Bali: And that's the website. If you just go there at the very… Which one are you in right now? Can you see your site?
Jatinder Bali: Now don't go… yeah, oh, you were able to get into this one? Is there a login here?
Jatinder Bali: Yeah, sign up and login, right? See right there, okay.
Jatinder Bali: So you can… you can probably apply.
Jatinder Bali: See, all this, you need to…
Krish NAik: Let me test it out, I'm not done testing here.
Jatinder Bali: This is very cheap, like, it's 25 bucks for an hour.
Krish NAik: If something is cheap, I have to look into the throughput and other things, but let me do that. I'm not.
Jatinder Bali: Oh, you're getting H100 over… H100 over here, is what I'm saying. It's not… it's not taking… you're not even getting garbage, but this is…
Krish NAik: Basically all…
Krish NAik: Let me see then, because I can actually… I'll be registering. Fine, let me see this part, and then I will check.
Jatinder Bali: But this, sorry, the only problem is that, you people outside of India, they'll have to use, some sort of a VPN to India.
Jatinder Bali: cannot access this site from outside India. And do you need some, some Azar card, or they have another card now.
Jatinder Bali: So you need that also to… to register, but I think…
Krish NAik: Because more directly, Digilocker is mentioned, no, so I feel Digilocker is for Indian residents and in our eyes only.
Jatinder Bali: And there is something else also. Maybe an organization also. Krishna can become an organization also over here, and then they can have.
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, I saw that, like, MSME and a few other startups on MSME is there, actually.
Krish NAik: That's right.
Krish NAik: Project Linea…
Jatinder Bali: If your student, it's also free, actually. It's, like, very good.
Krish NAik: Okay, then again, Indian students only, or US students?
Krish NAik: For sure, it has to be Indian, I feel.
Krish NAik: Alright, let me see. I will explore this one. Till no, I've not explored this one, let me see, and a few others in the AI space, if they have done it, I will ask them also.
Jatinder Bali: Sounds good. Thank you so much, Paul.
Krish NAik: A few folks are there in IAC and IT, I will ask them once, have they tested it out?
Jatinder Bali: Yeah, I mean, yeah.
Krish NAik: Thanks for informing this one, yeah.
Krish NAik: Abhisheikh?
Abhishek: Hey, hi, hi, hi, Paul. Thanks for the session. So, just wanted to understand, like, do we have the, course content for the leadership batch as well?
Krish NAik: No, no, see, that, I think Mike will be coming. He… that launch will be there around in the month of May. See, that batch, I'm not planning. So, really, I have zero idea, okay, about that.
Abhishek: We'll put my mind.
Krish NAik: My main focus is that the batch that I will be launching, the next one, that plan I can share you around March 3rd week. Just think, in your course only in between that, I will show you that this is the next plan that I…
Krish NAik: Okay, launching one.
lalit.javale: Mank will actually, like, he's working on that, because leadership batches are much shorter.
Abhishek: meaning.
Krish NAik: 9 months or 6 months?
lalit.javale: Yeah, so now, actually, now I'm in a dilemma, right? So I also want to join the batch which you will be starting, and then the leadership one, so…
Krish NAik: No, no, my timings will be unique, it… that's why morning.
lalit.javale: Because I am planning Subha Subha Khatam Kardu, that is the idea.
Krish NAik: So that…
lalit.javale: my day, okay, like, morning 6 or 6.30, let me see, like, what's… because even for me, I feel if I make a commitment at morning 6, my lifestyle changes will be there a lot. So, let me see, like, what happens, but, my syllabus, I will be making it ready by, third week of March, and I'll be showcasing it to you.
Abhishek: So, the reason I'm asking, right, so I have around, around 15 and a half years of experience, and then…
lalit.javale: I have never done this, deep learning training and all these things, right? And then, if I want to go to the, on the leadership side, so that, that, that…
lalit.javale: So there are two lines, right? Don't do two batches, and then if I enroll for both.
Abhishek: It'll be too hectic for me as well.
lalit.javale: Generally, I don't think the leadership batches will be…
lalit.javale: In the morning. But the morning slot for Mike is empty. I know that Mike is right now, he can take up the slot.
lalit.javale: So, just wait, because even I'm not sure, because in your course, Meng will be coming for one module, that is the MCP module, I will request him to come.
lalit.javale: Because I think, on 13th, I have a flight, so, like, if he comes and he will take, I will ask him and I can delegate him that information. Okay, so you guys can directly ask him also. So let me plan for that, because that MCP module, it's really, like, I don't feel it so much.
Krish NAik: Technical stuff, okay, but very, very easy. If I'm not available, then I can ask.
Krish NAik: Okay, so just give me time, let me work on that, and then probably I can let you know. Take the update from me around end of March or starting of April.
Abhishek: Okay, and what would be the, proximal, approximate total cost, like, you know, the Krishnak fees and the, infrastructure which we have to pay? So, any idea around that?
Krish NAik: See, I have to do the calculation. No.
Abhishek: Okay, notice here.
Krish NAik: still a rough calculation, because to train a GPT, you need 6 hours with 6 GPUs. I know the rough estimation comes close to $200. So, generally, like,
Krish NAik: Before that, if… before enrolling, I'll be doing a one-two meeting. I am not taking, like, it's open for everyone. It will be closed for very, like, few folks only, because of whom I.
Abhishek: Mmm, better.
Krish NAik: They are willing to spend. That's why first I will do a one-two meeting, and then simply I will tell you, okay, if it's not there, leave it. It's not… this course is not for you, you can go and enroll in this course.
Krish NAik: That will be a one-to-one meeting, that's why, like, you guys will come, anybody is coming, they will come to the sales team, from sales team to me. Then comes the payment.
Krish NAik: Once I don't approve then, because it becomes a hectic for me, no? Then, if they think that, okay, Paul is taking this one later on, suddenly, okay, I don't want them. The expectation before purchasing the course should be clear, that's why.
Abhishek: I understand. Cool.
Krish NAik: So that's say something, an initiative with respect to that costing will also be high, and US students, generally Canada, Mexico, we do have close to, like, 2,000 students, so all those students and everywhere will be focusing on only them. Indian students, I'm letting you know, but not everywhere, because my idea is let's keep it
Krish NAik: 100 folks is the maximum that I'm planning.
Abhishek: Okay. Not more than that.
lalit.javale: Sure, thanks, thanks.
lalit.javale: Hello?
lalit.javale: Hey, hi. Hello, Paul.
lalit.javale: So, my question… I have two questions. So, first is, like, I have around 16 plus years of experience in, QA and architecting automation framework. So, what do you suggest me for this? Like, what kind of
lalit.javale: study, or…
lalit.javale: jobs I should try for. And another one is, is there a… see, right now, rather than changing, just think about incorporating AI in your game.
lalit.javale: For example, how to make things automated in that, testing phase much more, through Playwright, just you have to think about what are the tools, how to make that automation.
lalit.javale: Using the current available tools for anything, like through, like, Copilot, through agents, how you can do that stuff. That will be mine, rather than directly making a transformation into that AI stuff.
lalit.javale: Okay.
Krish NAik: That makes more sense.
lalit.javale: And the second question was, like, are there any kind of, these freelance works for AI, ML?
lalit.javale: Right now, see, I don't have any freelance work.
lalit.javale: Not, not you, it's like…
lalit.javale: there are, like, multiple sites, but are there any works, freelance works, or something, like, you know? I'm not asking for the reference, it's just, like, like, are there any works, not from you?
Krish NAik: I'm not sure about that. Freelance stuff, really, like, I'm not, because I know there are so many websites, like Fiverr and others, but I'm not sure, because I feel that right now.
Krish NAik: The demand for freelancers is somehow less. There are certain things in the field of automation, okay, which needs to be annotated. There, they have a very high requirement. Or some creative type of field where you have there, the requirement is much more high.
lalit.javale: As compared to the IC.
lalit.javale: Okay.
Krish NAik: Okay, thank you.
Muthuvel Pandian: run upon.
Krish NAik: Yes, yes.
Muthuvel Pandian: Hello, Paul, my name is Mutual.
Krish NAik: Yes.
Muthuvel Pandian: Actually, Paul, the recent release by course from Krishnak Academy is the modern route now.
Krish NAik: Modern route, okay. You have purchased that course.
Muthuvel Pandian: No, no, no, I want to say about myself, my name is Raga as well. Okay, okay, okay, I got your name, it's fine. Now, okay, you are talking about the full-stack Route course that, yeah, actually, I want to say that, you are the mentor for me, you and Krishnak are mentor for me, passed, 4 years back.
Muthuvel Pandian: Currently, I'm working as a deep learning engineer.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Muthuvel Pandian: So, actually, from Krishna Kekarim also, I purchased Jenai Agent EKI.
Krish NAik: Hmm?
Muthuvel Pandian: So, is the moderate for the people? Is it… will it suit to me?
Krish NAik: See, if you have… if you are new to Gen AI, it means that in Gen AI, the three main stacks. Under Gen AI comes the LLM stack, the agent stack, and the RAG stack. Three stacks are there. If you are totally unfamiliar with these three stacks.
Krish NAik: I will suggest go ahead with the course.
Krish NAik: I hope I have made my point clear.
Muthuvel Pandian: You're clear, but I have, like, understanding how I created one of some of the projects.
Muthuvel Pandian: on Janay.
Krish NAik: Logic.
Krish NAik: Okay, if you have worked on the projects, then try to analyze, see.
Krish NAik: If you are spending some money, then you have to understand that the value that you are getting, if you feel that the value is there, because I feel that I have purchased some courses where only 10% of the content was totally unknown.
Krish NAik: And I actually purchased that because that particular 10%, nobody was providing, and it was very hard for me to search also. I have done the payment, I can understand. Now, in your case, do you feel that, like,
Krish NAik: See, whenever you spend, you have to invest time.
Krish NAik: Do you have the time? Do you think that it will be always be continuous in classes, or later on, if you're not looking into the live classes, can you attend the recordings? Think about that. If you're spending money, the commitment that you are making, always think from that.
Krish NAik: Because I know many students, they just purchase it, they keep it. That's a bad practice. So, always think from that. And, when you are picking up how many modules are unknown, take a ratio, known modules to unknown module.
Krish NAik: And if I feel that at least 20-30% is there, I probably might spend, because for me, $50, $100, fine. I can do it. But, not more than that.
Muthuvel Pandian: I see Godels and LLM Bass Safety Ethics.
Krish NAik: Alright, alright, I think Raghavendra also mentioned that same thing in the chat. Okay, like, yes, fine, like, if you want to go ahead with those topics, because those topics are not, like, really conceptual topics, those are much more application topics.
Krish NAik: Application topics, when I say that, it means that there is a dedicated library, you go, GadroCI, paper install, and you have to attach it with your LLM. That's the stuff. It means that if you spend at least 1 hour or two hours, a lot of things. But if you feel that, yes, I have lesser time, I cannot do the research, then go ahead. I hope I made my point.
Krish NAik: That is a.
Muthuvel Pandian: Yeah, huh.
Krish NAik: One thing is, I'm the guy, I know I can do it. Okay, if I spend some time.
Krish NAik: Absolutely, okay, so that's why I'm telling you, think from that perspective, because, see, if you are purchasing the course just for that topic. Now, that topic only be coming in your day 1, day 2, day 3. It will be coming, you have to wait 3 to 4 months, I hope. Yeah.
Krish NAik: You have to understand that thing, like, are you willing to wait for such a long time just to…
Muthuvel Pandian: No, no, no, on that.
Muthuvel Pandian: I cannot wait that much time, that's why I want to know about that.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's any external…
Muthuvel Pandian: If an extra tech stack are you teaching that modern route, I want to know that, that's it.
Krish NAik: Okay, no, so that's why, if you're feeling that you are not willing, then don't take it.
Krish NAik: Okay, that's why I'm telling for new guys with GenA, for rack batches also, I won't be suggesting that directly. If you feel that, yes, from here, because there, a lot of things will be in high level, because if you're trying to cover 3 stacks parallelly.
Krish NAik: within 5 months, it becomes very hard. I hope people understand that. The GenAI 3 stacks, the LLM SLM stack with 1 stack. Then the agent stack is the other stack and drag. We have separate 3 batches.
Krish NAik: For each tech. So, if you go within that jack-of-all-trades concept, fine, you will get a very good, holistic idea about the entire gen AI part, if you take this one. But if you're good in one-stop, like RAG, if you have actually gone in-depth. Now, the next come the agents. I will be much more focused toward that part.
Krish NAik: I hope I made my point.
Muthuvel Pandian: Actually, Paul, the courses which you have mentioned, I have purchased all the three.
Muthuvel Pandian: And I'm covering day-to-day… I'm recording both.
Krish NAik: If you have done that, then just for 3 things, don't get it. Later on, probably for RAG, let me see, like,
Krish NAik: Let's just wait, okay? Probably in the month of April, if you are going not with sessions, it's not for, like, teaching or something. General discussions, I'll be sharing those implementations, if you are actually looking for implementations.
Krish NAik: I have those implementations with me. I can directly share. From the implementation, just look and analyze. It's not such conceptual stuff. It's just like a layer. An application layer just sits on top of an LLM, or on top of your application doing filtering and those type of things. At least, those things I can provide.
Muthuvel Pandian: Okay, Paul, thank you, thank you.
Krish NAik: Okay, hold it.
Krish NAik: Alright, then I think, Mohanet is there. Yes, Mohanad?
Muhanned Alogaidi: Hi, Paul, can you hear me?
Krish NAik: Lean as I can.
Muhanned Alogaidi: Okay, so, finally, I got a chance to ask you.
Muhanned Alogaidi: Well, Paul, so I have a question about the batch you mentioned. So, can you just tell me the criteria, I mean, how to choose them, and based on experience, or, I mean, based on, I mean, their time to contribute, or what?
Krish NAik: Based on the project for which you have filled up the form.
Muhanned Alogaidi: For which one? No, you say there is another one, not… not the one for the graded product, and you say there is another one you're still planning to choose Armen Fox.
Krish NAik: Okay, okay, okay. No, no, no, see, that planning one will be the next one, see, but it is, like, after 2 months, you have at least 2 months. It's not, like, immediately after this course, I will start that.
Muhanned Alogaidi: Yes.
Krish NAik: You have 2 months, so you will get the information in your groups also. Like, as I'm planning it, say, I have showed you that plan. No, it's in planning phase, it means that from you guys, I will take some inputs.
Krish NAik: So, let's take, for example, this is the X Serbs 2. I told you, you know, so this is the plan. Can you see your advanced batch planning? So, it means that in this batch, I'll be taking at least 1 hour session.
Krish NAik: And in that session, probably one implementation that I can show you.
Krish NAik: This will be probably, like, in the month of April and May.
Krish NAik: a rough estimated time, but this final plan, I will share with you. And a few other topics, like metadata, enrichment, context track and comparison, these few things, I'll be taking it as extra classes. So I've kept this thing, but this finalized plan, once I'm back in Bangalore, I'll be sharing with you. So this one,
Krish NAik: It will take time for me.
Krish NAik: Okay, because… because for that, I have to look into the things where those topics are not there only, I have to pick up those topics, and then… so, it's a bit hard, it's… that's why. Just give me some time. I need… once I'm banned, I need at least two weeks to do the planning, and then the final draft syllables, I will share with you guys.
Muhanned Alogaidi: Great. So, okay, my second question, now we are getting, like, there is AI engineer, there is generative AI, generative AI engineer, there is deep learning engineer, but we're still not able to decide which path we will go to, or which one will be at least good for us. So, can you animate any…
Muhanned Alogaidi: Give us some hints, I mean, which one we can choose.
Krish NAik: Generally, like, the rule doesn't matter to me, really, like, it can be any role. I will be looking into the JD's job description.
Krish NAik: For job description in 2026, I've seen the old standards are written. It means that somewhere they will be writing tours of machine learning, and other things. It means that the old stuff you really need to know, with that, the new stuff which is right now trending in the market. Though the older stuff.
Krish NAik: it's still now much more viable. Like, people are using such algorithms of machine learning, statistics, and many, many products.
Krish NAik: But, the new things which are there, you need to adopt those things. So I feel that it's not about the rules. The Gen AI rule is a very generic rule, because the expectation in that rule, it can be, like, machine learning, deep learning, statistics, Python, a lot of other things. NLP, even they might add computer vision also.
Krish NAik: Okay, because you have to think that the same thing as a computer vision who is doing, he can actually do the same thing, but through agents. Inside an agent, he will wrap his main computer vision operation, or probably, like, detection and algorithm, and he can do the task.
Krish NAik: So, the stack is now bigger. So, for a single candidate, it becomes much more harder. But the three main pillars of Gen AI, you have to be good in that. That LLM, SLM space.
Krish NAik: The agent space, and the rag space.
Muhanned Alogaidi: Oh, great.
Krish NAik: So always remember, these three are the main pillars of Gen AI. The fundamentals are deep learning, computer vision, NLP, those things comes.
Krish NAik: But the three main pillars.
Muhanned Alogaidi: Okay, so my last question. After we finish this course, or this batch, do you plan any doubt sessions? I mean, like, even maybe one, two, three, especially for us, like, I mean, now, let's say 7, 2 or 3, and we are not able to ask all our questions. So, in general…
Krish NAik: Questions are there, directly drop me a mail, because I do take one-to-one, no? If something is important, some people want to ask me anything with respect to the job, and others, they drop me a mail. I share them the calendar link, if I'm not.
Muhanned Alogaidi: I sent you, I sent you three, four emails, the one up at the crash.com.
Krish NAik: No, no, no, no, I have not received your mail, because,
Krish NAik: See, I don't know which mail you have sent it, but marathon?
Muhanned Alogaidi: One about deep learning, and one about deep learning papers, the other one.
Krish NAik: It's APP at the rate Krishnaik. In which email have you sent?
Muhanned Alogaidi: Same thing, Muhammad, that'll be the same thing.
Krish NAik: champion here.
Krish NAik: Hmm, let's see… I don't think I… This is…
Muhanned Alogaidi: So, okay, just type again, sorry, the email, so I can…
Krish NAik: No, no, so I'm just sharing, do you have the Notion link with you?
Muhanned Alogaidi: Yes.
Krish NAik: Okay, in Notion, in every course, Here is the email. Email.
Krish NAik: Yeah, Punjasco.
Krish NAik: And everything was alright.
Muhanned Alogaidi: I am… I guess I haven't send a good call.
Krish NAik: Okay.com, no, no, no, no, the domain is .ain.
Muhanned Alogaidi: F, okay, okay, I see now.
Muhanned Alogaidi: Okay, great.
Muhanned Alogaidi: Okay, great. So, thank you, Seth. Thank you so much.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright, fine.
Krish NAik: All right, guys, so next week, we'll be starting with, multimodal tasks, PDF passing, getting those tables and those things. Again, next week, a lot of things, other things with respect to extra classes, that plan also I'll be sharing with you.
Krish NAik: Okay. Abhishek is asking, I have 2 years of experience in front-end development, and I'm planning to switch. Yes, you can make the switch, Abhishek. The same profile Rajat was from, he made the switch.
Krish NAik: Okay, from that, front end.
Krish NAik: Yes, right now the market is out. It's a good time, actually. Start giving interviews, Abhishek, if you want.
Krish NAik: Okay, and it's not com, it's dot, in, creationig.in, okay? Yes.
Krish NAik: Alright, guys, so I'll be concluding the session for today. Let's meet on Saturday and continue our discussion. Thank you, everyone. Bye-bye.
Krish NAik: Rohit, Rohit, Rohit, I think, at last, he raised hand.
Rohit Srivastava: So, I just…
Krish NAik: or 10.
Rohit Srivastava: See, Sergio, I'm a veteran, in software industry. I've been, like, working for the last 30 plus years.
Krish NAik: Yes, yes.
Rohit Srivastava: At this stage, yes, I have transformed myself into AI-based development.
Rohit Srivastava: And I've been, I'm working with Claude Code for now.
Rohit Srivastava: Last almost, like, 5-6 months now.
Rohit Srivastava: And, so… so there are… there are a couple of interesting fields which I'm, exploring out, like document management.
Rohit Srivastava: document classification, governance, security, and all that, and these all areas are involved in.
Rohit Srivastava: So what would be, I mean, what could be a right, you know, according to you, what do you think,
Krish NAik: I feel the things that you have told till now, okay, even I feel that AI governance.
Krish NAik: This will be the biggest thing in the next 3 to 4 years. Okay, the… it's something like…
Krish NAik: Only European Union is there, but why? Every country will have their own rules, I feel that. So that will be there.
Rohit Srivastava: No, no, it's got to come.
Krish NAik: Because that's the main trending. For example, in universities, if I say Stanford, CMU, UC Berkeley, this has been AI governance. It's actually, like, I feel like they are working much more. The speed is slow, but as compared to any other thing.
Krish NAik: For me, also, because,
Krish NAik: Even in my, like, I'm planning for a master's just based on that governance part only.
Krish NAik: Okay, but again, I have not finalized it, it's just a plan. But I feel, because the Apple product managers, few friends out there, a few seniors are there of mine, they are telling, governance will be, because till now, the main problem is nothing is standardized in the AI space.
Krish NAik: Everybody is doing according to your own thing. Okay, any, like, a lot of things are done in a controlled setting, which is really bad. Like, for others, it becomes very hard to replicate this stuff and actually test it out.
Rohit Srivastava: Yeah.
Krish NAik: not…
Rohit Srivastava: Okay.
Krish NAik: That is one good one that I told, like, governance, as you were telling. But document management, classification, yes, these are, like, problems, and I feel that, it will be there.
Rohit Srivastava: And it will be there, and purposely, I took this… I mean, I just wanted to get a deep understanding of RAD systems.
Rohit Srivastava: Because… That's one area where this, I mean, document management becomes very handy.
Krish NAik: You can work on, okay, yes, document management, then the other space, you can look into something like a version control layer for documents.
Rohit Srivastava: Mmm…
Krish NAik: It's just like, whatever in that document you were doing the change, like, through a git div, you can actually access that. You can look into that part. It means that a document versioning system, just like GitHub works.
Krish NAik: There you have GitDiff and others, but actually how to build it based on the document, you can explore that, like, line by line, exactly. If somebody in the RAG system first happens, the main problem, the document is there fine. The later on, with respect to the update. So, two approaches are there, delete that entire importing for the document, or exactly look into that and add it as a chunk.
Rohit Srivastava: But…
Krish NAik: Now, how to track that?
Krish NAik: Now, that part you can actually look into.
Krish NAik: most of the organizations have made it clear, like, I feel that nobody has open-sourced that stuff.
Rohit Srivastava: Right, right.
Rohit Srivastava: Right, and that's one area, you know, I mean, because, like, working with the specialized domain, like manufacturing AEC sector.
Rohit Srivastava: Where they have lots of AutoCAD files, and you know, I mean, versioning our AutoCAD files and getting diffs, those kind of things are sounding interesting.
Rohit Srivastava: And maybe… I don't know. Right now, I mean, I'll explore that.
Krish NAik: Yes, at least try to, at least you have to start with a small POC. Okay, gather some data, okay, through CloudCloud, plan that.
Rohit Srivastava: Okay, and try to look into the results.
Krish NAik: Okay. I close to him.
Rohit Srivastava: Because these are some things with respect to POCs, I feel that.
Krish NAik: You'll get a better idea, so that should you move ahead, gather more data, and in that way… because there are a lot of products that can be built, and in other species, actually, it's less, I feel.
Krish NAik: in civil space, automating plans, old plans which were there. Well, right now, one project is there. The underground sewers plans in Germany, for that, they are coming, like, with AI, how to do that stuff. Okay, so a few things are coming around in other domains. Yes, it looks good, but again.
Krish NAik: Less… more research is going on now.
Rohit Srivastava: Right, okay. And what, according to you, I mean, how's the scope of consulting in India? Because now, I think at this stage in my career.
Rohit Srivastava: I believe consulting would be a better option for me.
Krish NAik: Yes, even I feel that. Consulting is always a good option.
Rohit Srivastava: Most of the opportunities.
Krish NAik: because in your case, you have so much experience. So, by default, in our case also, like, few comes, okay, like, Krish does that. Like, it's always good, like, most of the times, they ask, like, what is the direction?
Krish NAik: which direction should I go ahead? Once we give the direction, then we are out of the system, in the initial 7 to 2 weeks only. We don't want to actually get into that product development. That is not the priority for us.
Krish NAik: Because I know people are there who can build that product, but to build that product, what is the right direction?
Krish NAik: That… Do I see one, too?
Rohit Srivastava: I want to take that route, like, I mean.
Rohit Srivastava: Getting the direction, and then establishing it, and then, you know.
Rohit Srivastava: I mean, end-to-end kind of a thing.
Krish NAik: Then, in that case, a little bit you need to explore other things also, a little bit, like… See, you have to be good in one cloud.
Krish NAik: That's the… for consulting, you have to be… just be good in one cloud, or automatically other things. Like, for me, only I do it in GCP or AWS, so AWS stack is required. Now, for any type of database solution, the entire data lifecycle, you have to understand. It means that, from the engineer's perspective, who will be handling the data, multiple pipelines, it… the tools can be anything. It can be, like, data brings, it can be…
Krish NAik: simple big data pipelines to pre-fed text, or anything that, however he is doing that, that is fine. Now, how the data is coming, tell BI part. If you have figured all the components between the data science component, the analyst component.
Krish NAik: I can say that you are good to go with consulting. You won't have any type of problems. That entire data lifecycle you have to go through once.
Rohit Srivastava: All right, all right. Yeah, thank you. Thank you so much.
Rohit Srivastava: Have a great day, Paul.
Krish NAik: Yeah, thank you.
Krish NAik: Alright… So, let's conclude. Bye-bye, everyone. Thanks for joining.